<topics>
    <topic>
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-eiffel-tower</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1889-04-02/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Worlds+Fair&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.058,0,1.116,1.41,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>THE EIFFEL TOWER
                    A Msht and Sensation for lisitor to
                    1arls
                    In view of the assurance of a
                    creditable representation of Hawaii
                    both in productions and person
                    agesat the Universal Exhibition of
                    this year in Paris a few facts rela
                    tive to the EiffeUower culled from
                    a late English paper may be of local
                    interest
                    The tower is named after its pro
                    jector Mr Eiffel now President of
                    the French Association of Engineers
                    He is famed in part -for the design
                    ing of a great bridge at Bordeaux
                    Although the Eiffel tower was orig
                    inally the conception mainly of an
                    ambition likened to that of Ameri
                    cans by the English paper referred
                    to for having the highest structure
                    in the world it was also early as
                    sumed that it would have uses in the
                    interest of science It is claimed
                    and anticipated that it will be very
                    raluable for observatory purposes
                    owing to the perfect clearness of the
                    air at its summit
                    The tower is to be one thousand
                    feet in height At the date of the
                    description here drawn upon it had
                    attained an altitude of 738 feet or
                    162 feet higher than any other build
                    ing on earth There were 180 men
                    employed then in its construction
                    100 preparing the lifts at the base
                    and 80 riveting the perfectly fitted
                    parts at top To avoid fatiguing the
                    workmen aloft in descending several
                    times a day for food a restaurant is
                    fitted up at a height of about 400
                    feet There are to bo four perman
                    ent restaurants for the refreshment
                    of visitors on the first stage of the
                    tower
                    A spiral stairway runs from the
                    ground to the summit of the tower
                    but it is believed that few if any in
                    experienced heads will be able to en
                    dure the strain of going round and
                    round or looking down from the
                    giddy heights Therefore there are
                    to be mechanical lifts to the top
                    four to the first stage two to the
                    second and thence one to the sum
                    mit the crown of observation The
                    final lift will have a capacity of 65
                    persons I1 ares will be 6 francs to
                    the first stage and 5 francs to the
                    top to be reduced on Sundays to 1
                    franc and 3 francs respectively No
                    visitors are allowed during construc
                    tion except on Sundays owing to
                    danger of accident from a hammer
                    or bolt falling from aloft Mr iffol
                    pays a weekly visit to thoworks The
                    workmeu have to endure severe cold
                    at the summit whore the thermome
                    ter sometimes registers several de
                    grees below zero
                    The panoramic view to be obtained
                    of the beautiful city of Paris and
                    environs froin the top of the Eiffel
                    tower must be loft to the readers
                    imagination until assisted by ac
                    counts from the Hawaiian Commis
                    sioners Col Spalding and Hon J
                    A Cummins or unofficial visitors
                    from these isies or descriptive writ
                    ers in the foreign press after ex
                    periencing the sensations of the
                    sublime ascension and prospect
                    UHfrnisMuaii</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068084/1889-04-26/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+Exhibition+1000+Feet+High+France+French+Worlds+Fair&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.335,-0.303,1.669,2.11,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>NEARLY 1000 FEET HIG&amp;
                    The Great Eiffel Tower at the
                    Paris Exposition.
                    How the Colossal Structure, Just
                    Completed, was Erected.
                    The great Eiffel tower at the Paris Exhi
                    bition has just been completed, and a de
                    scription of the colossal structure, with an
                    account of the way it was built, and a sketch
                    of its constructor, will bo appropriate at this
                    time. It is scarcely necessary to say that the
                    U
                    mm

                    Cologne
                    Cathedral,
                    511 ft.
                    The Eiffel Tower,
                    9S4 ft. The Great
                    Pyramid,
                    480 ft.
                    Eiffel tower is by far the highest structure in
                    the world. It presents a decidedly unique ap
                    pearance, too in general outline not unlike a
                    stack of four gigantic muskets with their
                    butts well and solidly spread and their bay
                    onets joining at their tips.
                    The Eiffel tower stands in the Champ de
                    Mars, almost on the left bank of the river
                    Seine, just in the rear of the Quai d'Orsay,
                    and in fact a part of its foundation is sunk
                    through an old arm of the river, which lias
                    been filled in these many years. Its base
                    covers a plot of ground 328 feet square, or
                    nearly two and a half acres in extent.
                    GUSTAVF. EIFFEL.
                    It Ls really at the base a group of four tow
                    ers, each nearly fifty feet square, placed at
                    the corners of the plot of ground, and in
                    clining toward each other as they rise at an
                    angle of fifty-four degrees. Each tower con
                    sists of four columns, bound together by
                    trusswork, and each column rests on a
                    masonry pier which is so built that the weight
                    of the column rests upon it squarely and not
                    at an ancle.
                    As the tower is 0S4 feet high. it will be
                    seen that the matter of providing a solid
                    foundation was one of great importance.
                    There was a lot of boring and digging befon
                    the spot upon which the tower stands was
                    finally selected.
                    The foundation rests upon a thick stratum
                    of sand and gravel. It may be well to say.
                    for the benefit of those who think sand is a
                    rather treacherous sort f ground, that a bed
                    of sand and gravel, away under ground, is
                    pretty solid stuff. One of the towers of the
                    Brooklyn Bridge rests on that sort of base.
                    The foundations of the two piers of the Eiffel
                    tower farthest from the Seine rest on sand
                    and gravel about twenty-five feet below the
                    surface of the ground. These foundations
                    were laid in open excavations, and consist
                    first of great solid platforms of beton, six
                    feet thick, and next of four stone piers which
                    rise to the surface to receive the iron col
                    umns. The foundations for the two piers nearest
                    the river were not so easily laid. It was
                    necessary to go thirty-five feet below the
                    surface of the ground, end this was sixteen
                    feet under water. So caissons had to be
                    used, as they were in building the Brooklyn
                    Bridge piers.
                    A caisson is in effect simply an enormous
                    iron box, without any cover, turned upside
                    down. The method of using it is to dig the
                    earth out from under it and allow it to
                    gradually settle as the excavation pro
                    gresses, meanwhile building the pier on top.
                    When the required depth is reached the cais
                    a .n itself is filled up with the beton, and it
                    forms the bottom layer of it a foundation.
                    A shaft is left running through the pier
                    auove for entrance and exit as the work goes
                    on, and the air in the caisson and shaft is
                    compressed to whatever is necessary to keep
                    the water out of the bottom. It is the prin
                    ciple of the diving bell modified.
                    Work on the foundations was begun on
                    January 28, 1887, and at the end of June they
                    were completed. Then began the labor of
                    setting up the innumerable pieces of iron of
                    which the tower is composed, and it went on
                    at a vapid rate, for each individual piece
                    came from the works of M. Eiffel, at Leval-lois-Pere
                    cut to its exact dimensions, fitted
                    and drilled, so that no modification was neces
                    sary at the place of operations. Up to a
                    height of about fifty feet the workmen re
                    quired no scaffolding to work upon, as each
                    pier supported itself, although each leaned
                    toward the others. Then an artificial support
                    had to le provided, as above that height, un
                    til the first platform was reached, the center
                    of gravity of each pier would fall outside of
                    the base.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1889-05-07/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Expo+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.038,-0.005,1.195,1.611,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Pxitia, May At 3 o'clock Sunday after
                    noon, M. Carnot, presidont of tho Ropublic,
                    soaompaniod by a number of ominont states
                    Mat, proceeded to .the Champs do Mars and
                    formally declared tho exposition open to tho
                    world. Thoro was much music and but lit
                    tle speech making. The city is profusely
                    Adorned with flags and banners; after dark
                    gut lights, oloctrioity and fireworks blend in
                    splendors noTor before equalled; and for
                    meatus to come Paris will be the Mecca of
                    th sightseers of the world.
                    MAcm.tniiT nxLL.
                    Xilherte, in 18GT and 1678, she has had
                    world's fairs, which wers at those times the
                    greatest yet held. The third, thich was
                    pasted Sunday, far oxceeds them in inagni
                    tod importanco and splendor as human
                    MtaeremonU of the present surpass those of
                    cto tho proximate past. In 1878 there
                    ware displayed inventions that in 1807 would
                    bars been esteemed chimorical; this year, in
                    tarn, soos an array that scarcoly the wildest
                    omthusiast had dreamed of cloven years ago.
                    Tho Actual physic.il oxtont of tho present ex
                    hibition correspondingly goes beyond that
                    f its prcleceior. The exposition covers 103
                    acres.
                    The gardens of the Hotel des Invalided
                    contain the exhibitions of tho French
                    colonies, of tho several ministers and of
                    social economy. At the Quai d'Orny aro
                    tho halls of agriculture, viticulture, INhorios
                    and general food products. The Trocudoro
                    gardens are given up to fruits and flowers
                    in tho open air and in glass houses. Tho
                    principal buildings aro clustered on the
                    Champs de Mars, where a century ago, somo
                    of tho great oponing scenes of the revolution
                    wero ouacted.
                    At tho ontranco, spanning the gateway
                    witu the vast archways of Ite base, rises tho
                    gigantic Eiffel tower, 'MO metres high. Pass
                    ing underneath it tho Central gardou is
                    i cached. This has a monumental fountain
                    BASE OF EIFFEL TOWER,
                    ia tho middlo, and is surrounded by build
                    ings containing exhibitions of flue arts,
                    boUos lettres, tho liberal arts, and various
                    departments of industry.
                    Those buildings stand on parallel lines and
                    ore crossed in their axis by a high gallery
                    manaounted by a doma which leads to th
                    hatt of machinery. Tho cost of tho build
                    ings in tho Champs do Mars, exclusivo of tho
                    Mffel tower, has been about (4,000,000, and
                    it is intended that they shall remain as per
                    aaaent structures. The total outlay author
                    ised for tho entire exposition U 38,600,000, of
                    wttch $000,000 is hold aa a rcerve fund.
                    The earthworks required a removal of
                    700,000 cubic foot. Tke drains and water
                    pipes of the Camps do Mars were lengthened
                    hf about two miles, and more than 40,009
                    ems of iron and steel wero u&amp;ed by the
                    holders. The hall of machinery is 1,309 feet
                    long and 150 feet high, covered with a roof
                    f iron, wood and glass, having a span of
                    380 feet in tho clear, the greatest ever at
                    tempted. A gullory extends around tke in
                    terior for the display of tho lighter classes of
                    machinery and from end to end run four un
                    ferofcen linos of shafting for distributing the
                    Beotivo power. Tho powor is dorived from a
                    proup of steam engines placed in one of
                    the touts, tho bollors of which transform
                    into steam forty tons of wator per hour.
                    The total energy is about 400 horse power.
                    TJio chief architectural feature of the ex
                    position is, of course, tho Eiffel tower, as
                    wore the Crystal Palace at London In 1851,
                    the iron lighthouse at Paris in 1807, tho groat
                    THE EIFFEL TOWZ&amp; VBOX THE BEINK
                    rotunda at Vionna in 1873, and the Trocadero
                    palace at Paris in 1878. This is the loftiest
                    structure eyer rahedjjy Iman, being about
                    064 feet high. The Washington monumont
                    now stands second, 55.5 feet. The Cologno
                    cathedral is 501 feot. Tho tower of Babol
                    was probably CS0 high. Moro than 7,000
                    tons of metal were us?d in building tho
                    Eiffel tower. Tho first sod was turned in
                    excavation for its foundation on January
                    28, 1887, and the whole work was completed
                    on March 31, 1889.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032018/1894-01-31/ed-1/?sp=15&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Worlds+Fair+1900+Exhibition&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.304,-0.08,1.608,1.608,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>The World's lair in 1900.
                    Already the air is' filled with rumors
                    respecting the exposition of 1900, says
                    a Paris letter in the Philadelphia Tel
                    graph. Already are the moans of the
                    Parisians rending the air beforehand,
                    for it is a Parisian peculiarity to detest
                    world's fairs in general, and those held
                    in their own city in particular. Quoth
                    a miserable native in heartrending ac
                    cents: "Whenever there is a great ex
                    hibition all our taxes go up-rtempo-rarily
                    we are told, but never by an ac
                    cident do they go down. I paid three
                    hundred and eighty francs in '77,
                    and for the same premises my taxes
                    are now three thousand and odd. We
                    are overrun by tourists; we are crowd
                    ed out of all the theaters; the cabmen
                    all go on strike; the cafes all put up
                    their prices. For several years before
                    all the streets one wants to go through
                    are closed to the public because the ex
                    hibition is being prepared, and for at
                    least a year after the same streets are
                    closed because the exhibition is being
                    demolished. All your country cousins
                    come to town and expect to stay with
                    you in an apartment you have always
                    found too cramped for the require
                    ments of yonr own family; and if I am
                    not lucky enough to be dead I shall
                    certainly move away before this large
                    misfortune falls upon this unhappy
                    place."
                    tj Happily all Paris is not so pessi
                    mistic as my friend, and the architects
                    are busy with their plans. All the
                    ground comprised in the exhibition of
                    '89 is to be included, as well as the por
                    tion of Cour la Heine that will inclose
                    the Palais 1' Industrie and its surround
                    ing gardens. We are to have an addi
                    tional bridge across the Seine which
                    will open a vista from the Place de la
                    Concorde straight through to the palace
                    of electricity, which is to be the cen
                    tral feature. Our rulers are greatly
                    bored about the Eiffel tower; but as
                    the concession was granted for twenty
                    years it has got to stand; but the arch
                    itects say consolingly that the 7 will
                    try and hide it as much as possible.
                    The sight of it vexes poetio souls,
                    and Francois Coppee, the author, who
                    is, by way of being, sthetio, wrote
                    a formal protest to the government at
                    the time of its erection to request that
                    the plan should not be carried out on
                    the ground that the Eiffel tower, being
                    ugly and ungainly, and furthermore
                    being visible from his windows, inter
                    fered with his flow of inspiration.
                    However, the tower was built never
                    theless, and, although we are deadly
                    tired of seeing it about, Coppee con
                    tinues to write, so evidently his flow
                    ol inspiration was only impeded and
                    not permanently plugged up. Further
                    more, we are to have a branch exhibit
                    at Versailles, which will rouse that
                    sleepy little town from its chief ou
                    pation of listening to the grass grow
                    ing in the streets. In the splendid
                    park of Versailles, on either side of
                    the grand canal, is to be the retro
                    spective history of gardens throughout
                    the ages.
                    The Hanging Gardens of Babylon,
                    that were counted among the wonders
                    of the world, are to be reproduced in
                    miniature; Japanese gardens, Persian
                    gardens, the Italian garden of the
                    renaissance and French and English
                    gardens of different epochs. The
                    Grand canal itself is to be used for the
                    exhibition of one of the floating gar
                    dens cultivated by the Aztecs in Mex
                    ico before the Spanish conquest of the
                    country. The center of the canal is to
                    be occupied by a large island built on
                    piles, with bridges connecting it with
                    the two shores, which is to have
                    aquaria, grottoes and cascades, with
                    cages for aquatic birds, and the great
                    sheet of water is to be additionally or
                    namented, by an exact reproduction of
                    the little fleet of elegant boats that
                    Louis XIV. launched on its surface
                    when Versailles was first built All
                    this sounds most imposing; but we are
                    devoutly thankful that the time for it
                    has not yet come. It is like the 6tory
                    of the philosopher who was to teach
                    the king's donkey to speak in a year's
                    time, on pain of death, and never
                    bothered about the penalty on the
                    crowd tMt the kin? mLrht UJ
                    the "doSkey "might' die, or ha
                    himself might die, and whatever hap
                    pened he had a year to the good. So,
                    as we have seven years before us, we
                    do not yet as a rule wail about future
                    contingencies.
                    POLANDCHINA PIGS AND SHORT
                    horns, bred by J. H. Taylor, Pearl, Eas.
                    MEGGlNCUBaT0nS0rilY$1Q
                    F.M.CUEYlA,Boxl51,Lincoln,NebV I v
                    AGE
                    Wanted. Liberal Salary
                    AthotneortotrTl. Team rural, hrd
                    free. P. O. VICKKBY, AaoiU, He.
                    AND TUMORS aolan tlfUally
                    I treated and cured. No knife.
                    Rook ft. Dr. L. II. tiralla-ay.
                    1 SO SkMIU A, Clarlaaali, Ohio.
                    FOR LADIES ONLYJXTi
                    Valuable Secret that cost me 15.00 and a Rubber Shield for SOetSi
                    Mia f ft.ftTlAN tX!.,ofi KlVMSyiHUIAflfX, fTfo
                    BH0RTHAND gong raSIkBMkataklapiB. Sum
                    ptoat tat an Tm, eoqaM to iha tuuatiaaa ewun4
                    rtuMM W BatM,Titarrpt m Shunt DrartraM. ft. H.
                    lira (art, laoaai dtf Bartrnai UoMtntv. iaaaw Utf. at
                    Permanently Cured
                    Home treatment. 0 to t35.
                    Bend stamp for hook.
                    jno. B. Harris, Port Payne, Ala.
                    ftr A MnNTH"i"!!I"i!f"7;
                    MU a montn to dUtfiMM circular,, warypwu momuij. omii
                    U oar modi and contract free. Send 10 cti. for pottage, packing,
                    f.'.,. Wi MtinKwim VSWS SUI'PI.Y CO.Cmca.ia In.
                    $COC Agent's profltspermonth. Will
                    J Cm J prove It or pay forfeit. New arti
                    cles juat oat. A L60 sample and terms free. Try
                    us. Chideater Son, 38 Bond at, N. Y.
                    MICROBE cause disease; Microbe Killer
                    kills microbes. Cures all diseases. Write
                    for agency. Big money: exclusive control. If
                    sick write for pampnlet. Try our granules;
                    finest laxative In the world; 250 postpaid.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83040198/1899-02-03/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+France+French+Paris+Exhibition+Worlds+Fair+Ladder+Clouds&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.241,-0.074,1.483,1.483,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>A LADDER FROM THE CLOUDS
                    Bach Will Be the Appearance of the
                    Eiffel Tower of Parts When
                    Painted.
                    The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
                    of esthetic temperament, must go.
                    The Eiffel tower, say the gentlemen
                    who know the law, must stay for some
                    years yet. The Eiffel tower, say the
                    esthetes. Is ugly, discouraging to the
                    eye and an all-round nightmare. "Scaf
                    fold I cries the carper. "Down with it
                    It has no place in esthetic Paris,"
                    "Impossible! objects the law. "When
                    the company took a lease of it they
                    got it for a term of 20 years.. You
                    can't break the lease, and the time is
                    nowhere up.
                    "But, urges the esthete, "look at
                    the shape, look at the size, look at the
                    color! Is not the whole thing hideous"?
                    If we can't destroy it we can at least
                    improve it and lessen the offense to
                    our senses."
                    And so the Eiffel tower is going to be
                    metamorphosed. It has. been in color
                    a reddish brown, and it is the color to
                    which the gentlemen with the fine ideas
                    have long objected. They have called
                    the tower a shameless creation and re
                    peatedly ridiculed the commonplace
                    tone of hue. And now they have pre
                    v ailed, and the lower is going to be a
                    thing of beauty, so far as that goes.
                    Silver white is the color agreed upon,
                    and it is urged that when the army of
                    workmen have finished their painting
                    the huge structure will look really not
                    so bad after all. Ilalf a hundred men
                    will be employed on the building, work
                    ing hard every day for two months.
                    And 50,000 kilogrammes of paint will
                    be used up before the Eiffel tower has
                    finally lost its brickdust coat and finds
                    itself arrayed in the poetic covering
                    which the esthetes have advised. Two
                    coats of paint will be applied and the
                    brushes will be busy.
                    It has been objected that the tbwer
                    has always had the appearance or hav
                    ing been cast up in inartistic form by
                    a careless earth. The tower has seemed
                    to rise awkwardly from the ground,
                    the critical have said. Why not give
                    it such an arrangement as would sug
                    gest the idea of dropping from the
                    clouds? That would be a pleasing fan
                    cy, and if the huge tower were lighted
                    at regular intervals it would present a
                    picture as of a brilliant creature of the
                    clouds, and all the world would be lost
                    in admiration. These plans were sug
                    gested when the exposition of 1900 were
                    tinder discussion, and they have been
                    adopted. A ladder from the clouds.
                    That was tbe idea. 'And with that the
                    esthetic taste, was forced to be sat
                    isfied.
                    The Eiffel tower has long been the
                    universal bed lamp of Paris. The great
                    candle in the top would be sadly miss-d,
                    even by those who have fought agair.&amp;t
                    the continuance of the structure. That
                    ever-swaying lantern is one of the won
                    ders of the French capital. Y. Her
                    aid.
                    Kicked All Around.
                    A correspondence is being published
                    In the Times on the subject of "French
                    Feeling Toward Englishmen." A Mr.
                    Jackson has written to that paper to
                    repeat that at Caen recently a student
                    went out of his way to publiely insult
                    Great Britain. As a boy I was first for
                    some years at school in Paris. I -was
                    then kicked for being an Englishman;
                    later I was transferred to a school in
                    England, where I was kicked for being
                    a Frenchman. Comment is unneces
                    sary. London Truth.
                    Bis Only neeoorie.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1903-10-25/ed-1/?sp=24&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Doomed+Rocks+Wind+Paris+France+French+Gustav&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.216,-0.072,1.431,1.431,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>THE Eiffel Tower must come down.
                    The authorities of Paris have so decreed.
                    This iron spire, the tallest structure in the
                    world, and the engineering feat of the last cen
                    tury, \.i regarded as a dangerous plaything.
                    When a high wind blows from the south the great
                    ribbed structure trembles like a frightened horse.
                    But let a stiff breeze come bowling down from the
                    north and the tower vibrates until the china rattles in
                    the cafes, and to those in the observatory at the apex the
                    sensation is that of a ship fossed by heavy seas.
                    The fact that the tower is more'sensitive to a wind
                    from the north than from the south is regarded as proof
                    of the structural weakness, and from this springs the
                    theory of danger of collapse.
                    It is almost twenty years since Gustav Eiffel began
                    the work of building his sky-scraper. The mark of com
                    pletion was set for 1889, Exposition year, and on March 31
                    of that year the tower was thrown open to the public. It
                    wa« the leading attraction of the big show, and it has
                    not since ceased to attract attention and coin.
                    The cost of building the structure was more than
                    $1,000,000. Of that amount the French government appro
                    priated $29L',000. Eiffel supplied the remainder, trusting
                    for his reimbursement to the receipts from admission fees
                    and other sources.
                    In this he was not uisappolnted, as the profits of the
                    first year were almost sufficient to make him whole.
                    The lease held by Eiffel will expire in next March, and
                    then, if the present plans of the city fathers are realized,
                    the work of razing the unique structure will be started.
                    The plan is to sell the tower to the highest bidder, the
                    purchaser to be given a certain time in which to remove
                    what Paris regards as almost a public menace.
                    Except as a curio and an Investment for its builder,
                    the tower has been somewhat of a failure.
                    Much was expected in the scientific world from the
                    metaphorical observatory, with its physical and biological
                    laboratories, all 954 feet above ground. But little has
                    come of this, the enterprise having taken on a rather
                    commercial aspect.
                    The Eiffel Tower will ever be considered a colossa*
                    feat of engineering.
                    Tlhese Stria! Ihxean F®ds ire nsudhes hM
                    .'v_V- Ir 'mJf.A?j -i?'^^t Vk^T*i^*v*
                    THE beanstalk up which Jack, the Giant Killer,
                    climbed to fame has been sung and pictured until
                    even little Emma and Annie and Jeannette and
                    Joe, sprawled there on the nursery floor, can tell
                    of its sturdy trunk, of its stout, ladder-like branches, of
                    Its leathery leaves, which the eager hands of their hero.
                    Jack, could not crush, though he clutched them ever so
                    tightly.
                    They can tell you that this fabled beanstalk was so
                    tall that "Oo! you jest couldn't see the top uv it, so you
                    couldn't."
                    DRINKERS IN TWO CLASSES
                    ==Mlsery and L,Mxtuiry==
                    BOTH CLAIM THEIR VICTIMS OF LIQUOR
                    LONDON, August 17.
                    WOMEN who drink are classified by the experts
                    into two sections—misery drinkers and luxury
                    drinkers.
                    Speaking broadly, the misery drinkers come
                    from the very poor, the luxury drinkers from the rich.
                    But whatever the cause which first sends them to drink
                    the ultimate results are the same—a falling birth-rate, a
                    rising death-rate among infants and the physical degen
                    eration of the race.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1917-04-23/ed-1/seq-5/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Paris. Stars and stripes hung be
                    side tri-color on Eiffel tower Sunday,
                    afternoon, while formal salute of 21
                    guns was fired in its fconor. It was
                    United States day in Paris and Amer
                    ican flags -were everywhere.
                    New York. Local newspapers
                    adopt resolution criticizing press
                    censorship provision of espionage
                    bill "assault upon very foundation ol
                    our free institutions, freedom ol
                    thought and freedom of speech."</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1907-05-18/ed-1/?sp=26&amp;q=Dangerous+Painting+World+Eiffel+Tower+Paris+France+French+Republic+Gustav&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.149,-0.412,1.111,2.36,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>The Trocadero m Seen Through the
                    "Lege" of the Tower.
                    Height of the Great Tower
                    as Compared to Some of
                    the World's Tallest
                    Structures.
                    Special Correspondence of The Star.
                    PARIS, May A, 1907.
                    A painter has Just fallen from the Eiffel
                    Tower. Four more men must fall to make
                    the awful average of the most dangerous
                    painting Job in the world?repeated every
                    six years only.
                    They are repainting the Eiffel Tower,
                    and all Paris is concerned about the color,
                    on which depends whether the gigantic
                    mass of iron shall be the eyesore or the
                    glory of the capital.
                    Its first shade was "dead leaf," In 1889.
                    When the sun lit it up to hazy golden with
                    an unreal effect of Jeweler's fragility, even
                    the artists who now corse it admitted that
                    the Eiffel Tower had its nobility.
                    In 1896, after immense discussion, they
                    repainted It orange, magnetic currents
                    even more than light and weather having
                    turned it to a dingy chocolate, heavy and
                    obtrusive. In strong sun the orange
                    showed gleaming copper or red gold. Oscar
                    Wilde declared It magnificent. Puvis de
                    Chavannes threatened to blow It up with
                    dynamite. From this period dated the bad
                    name the tower acquired as a colossal
                    piece of engineering vulgarity, usurping
                    the artistic note of Paris.
                    Then, for the exposition, they painted it
                    "sun color." In bright lights the tower
                    became a thing of glory once again.
                    "All Depends Upon the Faint."
                    "All depends upon the paint!" declares
                    the city's architect, Bouyard, "a fact
                    which shows the utter inartistic character
                    of the Titan 1^3 intruder. The pyramids ol
                    Egypt were originally cased with gleaming
                    marble; but its present lack does not
                    detract from the artistic appropriateness
                    of the pyramids to their situation!"
                    The tower gleamed sun color seven years
                    agoi But the atmospheric electricity received
                    every hour since then by such an
                    unprecedented mass of iron reaching into
                    the air so high is Incalculable. Conducting
                    tubes a foot and a half in diameter
                    lead it down the four niles to flftv feet be
                    low the water-bearing stratum; but the
                    effect on the paint la there for every one
                    to see. It does not crack the paint off.
                    The paint simply disappears, leaving the
                    ugly chocolate, the dingy brown of the
                    oxidising iron.
                    It Is the tower's way of "calling for new
                    victims. Fifty painters, working continuously
                    together, take three months to do a
                    ingle coat Few tourists realise- the immense
                    proportions of the tower, but
                    Parisian!, by experience, show you a peculiar
                    phenomenon of Its deceptive symmetry.
                    They take you In a cab close to the
                    tower. It looks heavy and chunky. It
                    seems sinking into the earth from lU
                    weight. Half a mile distant from that
                    oab the tower grows higher and slenderer.
                    It seems to lift Itself from the earth, like
                    a person rising from his knees. "Why, It's
                    bigger than before!" you say. At a mil*
                    distant-It seems quite as near. The river
                    boats ttmt flit beside It now look tiny. The
                    buildings round about are growing small.
                    But the tower grows! Then at two miles?
                    from the heights above Passy?It appears
                    A 4kin? A# litfhtnMa hl alAn^nrAf
                    Efc IIIIUB Vi u fc?v? gutiUVBWi ?and
                    more open In Its lacework than when
                    you gaped at its foot almost disappointed!
                    In a country town thirty miles from
                    Paris I have sat at night and watched Its
                    leaxchltsht!
                    Some Comparisons.
                    Tou think Niagara Falls are high? They
                    are 105 feet, and St. Paul's Cathedral, Lon- 1
                    don. is 404 feet. Niagara Falls could de
                    scend from below St. Paul's dome. Now
                    place St. Paul's beside the Eiffel tower. It
                    reaches only to the second platform of the
                    tower?the real beginning of its slender
                    shaftl
                    Place the Eiffel tower beside the greatest
                    buildings of the world. The great pyramid
                    does not reach to Its Intermediate platform.
                    Neither does the spire of the Cologne 1
                    Cathedral.
                    Only one 'set of buildings, nevertheless,
                    are higher than the Cologne Cathedral
                    Bplre. They are the sky-scrapers of American
                    dtles, the tallest actually existing being,
                    say, 6S6 feet high. It would not reach to
                    the tower's intermediate platform, either.
                    The loftiest masonry construction In the
                    world is to be the Singer building extension,
                    at the corner of Liberty street and
                    Broadway, New Torlc. Beating any other J i
                    American sky-scraper by 57 feet, it will i
                    stick 612 feet into the air. And yet even j
                    It will not reach to the Eiffel tower's inter- i
                    mediate platform 1
                    You can easily detect this intermediate i
                    platform half way up the slender shaft of 3
                    the Eiffel tower. In the nearer photographs j
                    It shows for what it is?a mere platform
                    for styftlng passengers from one set of ele- t
                    vators to another, built In the center of the 1
                    the time you git left. This yere man. Bob
                    Hampton, Is my prisoner, an' I'll take him
                    to Cheyenne. If I have ter brain every tough t
                    in Glencaid to do It. Thet's me, gents." 1
                    "Oh, come oft; you can't run your notions j
                    igin the whole blame moral sentiment of c
                    this camp." c</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1912-09-14/ed-1/seq-23/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>IParis
                    fV
                    Birdseye View of Paris Taken From the Top of the Eiffel Tower. In the Distance
                    May Be Seen the Arc de Triomphe, Around
                    Which Is Situated the Most Fashionable and Aristocratic Residential Quarter in
                    Paris.
                    (PHOTOGRAPH BY COURTESY OF NEWMAN TRAVELTALKS.)

                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1900-05-20/ed-1/?sp=43&amp;q=Feet+Tower+Eiffel+Paris+France+French+Worlds+Fair+Exhibition&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.322,-0.082,1.644,1.644,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033162/1900-05-18/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Paris+Exposition&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.372,-0.087,1.744,1.744,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1907-03-10/ed-1/?sp=47&amp;q=Eiffel+Tower+Gustav+Paris+France+French+Republic&amp;r=-0.196,0.586,0.858,0.578,0&amp;st=text</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1912-09-14/ed-1/seq-23/ocr/</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1912-04-28/ed-1/seq-8/ocr/</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1954-05-23/ed-1/seq-123/ocr/</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
    <topic>
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-babe-ruth</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86063381/1916-10-09/ed-1/seq-4/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    &amp;amp;#34;BABE&amp;amp;#34; RUTH PITCHES
                    SECOND FOR BOSTON
                    Babe Ruth.
                    Babe Ruth, the Red Sox pitcher, is
                    just about as valuable for his hit
                    ting as for his pitching. Ruth has
                    shown so much natural talent at bat
                    that Bill Carrigan has seriously con
                    sidered playing bim in the outfield
                    when he isn&amp;apos;t pitching
                    SUBMARINE ACTIVE
                    (Continued from Page 1)
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045211/1917-07-02/ed-1/seq-10/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Babe Ruth Is Lucky to Get Off So Easily After Hittimj Umpire
                    FAR be It from ua to wish any guy haid luck, but It appears that Babo Ruth
                    escftpefl too easily after his fight with Umplro Owens on tho ball field. Ban
                    Johnson dismissed the matter with a flno of $100 nnd a suspension of ono week.
                    This does not seem enough, nnd It Is certain that a player of less lmportanro
                    would have been treated rather harshly. Ruth is one of tho stars of tho lcaguo .
                    and a prolonged nbsenco would havo ruined Boston&amp;apos;s pennant chances.
                    Also
                    tho
                    gate receipts would have suffered. So Bnttllns Ban beenme as meek ns a lamb
                    and decided to &amp;#34;give the boy another chance.&amp;#34;
                    The bad feature of this case Is that It will cnconrago others to pull tho same
                    Btuff. A week&amp;apos;s layoff nnd $100 fine Is nice, gentle punishment,
                    nnd
                    tho
                    chances
                    are that some playora would pay twice as much for a shot at nn
                    umpire&amp;apos;s
                    Jaw.
                    It cost McGraw $500 for punching Byron under tho grnnd stand nnd
                    Ruth&amp;apos;a
                    of
                    fense was more flagrant thnn that. Ban seems to havo mado another mistake.
                    Ho should, have used Ruth ns a horrlblo example and soaked him with a long
                    layoff and a healthy tine.
                    The dope has run to form at Pittsburgh. Barney Dreyfuss showed Jimmy
                    Callahan the way to the gate nnd ho departed from tho city of smoke amid the
                    crash and clatter of tho tlnwnro which was dragging behind. Callahan barf not
                    made good with the Pirates nnd last year thero was talk of canning him. Ho
                    is not popular with the players nnd they wouldn&amp;apos;t work for him.
                    Thls
                    also
                    was
                    the case when Jimmy was boss of the Whlto Sox. His ability was great, but his
                    personality negative.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1918-09-06/ed-1/seq-11/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Fourth Inning Decides
                    Battle
                    By W. J. Macbeth
                    CHICAGO, Sept. 5.?The Boston Red
                    Sox won the opening gama of the
                    series for the world&amp;apos;s baseball cham?
                    pionship of 1918 from the Chicago
                    Cubs at Comiskey Park this afternoon.
                    Much of the customary hurrah of this
                    annual classic was lacking, but the
                    game was such a one as to llvs long in
                    the annals of the diamond sport
                    In a wonderful pitching duel, In
                    which each manager staked his most for?
                    midable southpaw, the mighty &amp;#34;Babo&amp;#34;
                    Ruth vanquished the giant Vaughn by
                    a score of 1 to 0. Though beaten,
                    neither Vaughn nor tho supporting
                    Cub cast was in any way disgraced.
                    It was such a game as one seldom i
                    sees in the final title battles, some- i
                    thing which approached the acme of j
                    perfection in every line.. As had been
                    predicted, this one game at least made j
                    good the prophecy that sterling box
                    work would predominate. Perhaps
                    because of the excellence of the rival
                    pitchers the hard fought engagement
                    did not develop the customary thrills
                    one looks for in the blue ribbon of
                    sports.
                    A Perfect Game
                    The game was just a bit too perfect
                    to be as interesting as it might. There
                    were no errors, either of commission
                    or omission. There were wonderful
                    fielding plays, it is true, but these
                    were the exception rather than the
                    rule, and they were, turned with a
                    daring that made them appear scarce?
                    ly part of mechanical, machine-like
                    precision.
                    To such excellent advantage did the
                    rival boxmen appear that from the
                    start it seemed but a question of
                    which side would first score. The. fur?
                    ther they went the stronger and bet?
                    ter both Ruth and Vaughn appeared
                    to grow. Rig Jim was unfortunate
                    enough to havp the big break against
                    him. Tltis was in the fourth inning,
                    when was seen the or.I.v vital action
                    of the afternoon.
                    Vaughn, whose game on the whole
                    was quite the equal of Ruth&amp;apos;s wizadrry,
                    %vas unfortunate enough to han ? 1 out
                    the first pa-.s of the game to llave
                    Shean, first, up in the fourth, nnci from
                    that gift resulted the only run of the.
                    day, There followed two clean singles,
                    from the bats of White.man and Mc
                    Innis, the punch required to earn
                    Shcan&amp;apos;s passage home.
                    If Vaughn is tn he criticized at all
                    for hi? slight lapse he should not. be
                    criticized jor handing over the free
                    ticket to Shean, but for apparent care
                    le ? , in &amp;apos; ? tossing to Whitt man
                    and Mclnnis later when he was in
                    tight quarters. Every ball player and
                    student of the game knows that Jim
                    Vaughn lias nothing to brag about in
                    the way of a curve ball. His fast one
                    is his chief stock in trade. Yet Vaughn,
                    in the hole, fed curve balls both to
                    Whiteman and Mclnnis, and it was the se
                    offerings against which the Red Sox
                    batters lea.: to assure the visitors
                    first blood of the tilt.
                    Cold Wave Mars Attendance
                    Py and by we will get down to the
                    vitals of the game in question. A
                    word or two now on the general color
                    scheme, or rather lack of color. The
                    crowd seemed smaller than th? re?
                    ported 19,000 odd. Perhaps many were
                    kept, away by the cold wave which hit
                    the Windy City over night, following
                    a doing?. There was nol the customary
                    interest one expects in Chicago.
                    The series attracted less attention
                    from the start, than the pageant in
                    Grant Park. If any betting developed
                    over the result of this particular series
                    those who made the wagers took good
                    care to conceal their identity. In
                    short, it was a sort of bust, this open?
                    ing gam? of the 1918 baseball classic.
                    Kven the players involved seemed to
                    show less dash and spirit, than in years
                    gone by. Perhaps the knowledge that
                    the game has given away to war is too
                    great an obsession and oppression for
                    a profession which has been pampered
                    and petted after the fashion of tem?
                    peramental operatic stars.
                    A genuine brand of world series
                    weather prevailed. The wind swept in
                    off&amp;apos; thp lake with penetrating force so
                    that most, everybody was frozen to the
                    marrow bef?te play was called.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1918-09-12/ed-1/seq-11/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Eighth Inning (Cubs) Baitier batted
                    In place of Deal. Whiteman canto in
                    fast and took Barber&amp;apos;s liner off the top
                    of the grass and made a complete som
                    ersault. O&amp;apos;Farrell batted for KUlefer.
                    O&amp;apos;Farrell sent a high fly to Scott. Mc
                    Cabe batted for Tyler. Whiteman wat
                    withdrawn nt this point and Ruth was
                    sent to left field for Boston. Whltoman
                    hurt his neck In making the catch of
                    Barber&amp;apos;s drive. McCabo fouled out to
                    Scott.
                    i!lghth Inning (Sox) Hendrlx and
                    O&amp;apos;Farrell became the battery for Chi
                    cago and Zelder went to third In place
                    of Deal. Mclnnls filed out to Mann.
                    Scott lofted to PaBkert. Thomas also
                    filed out to Paskert.
                    Ninth Inning (Cubs) Flack up. Ball
                    one. Strike one. Ball two. Strike two,
                    a foul. Ball three. Flack fouled to
                    Thomas. Hollocher filed out to Ruth.
                    Mann up. Ball one. Strike one. Rail
                    two. Mann grounded to Shan, who
                    threw to Mclnnls for the out that ended
                    the world&amp;apos;s aerie? of 1918.
                    FOB &amp;#34;Sl&amp;apos;X&amp;#34; MMOKI1 FI1M).
                    The Holy Names and the Macombs A.
                    C. will start their three game sorlcs for
                    Tub Sun Tobacco Fund at the Polo
                    Grounds on Sunday. There will be no
                    admission fee. On Sunday afternoon nt
                    West Side Park, Jersey City, tho S5lcg
                    feld Follies will play the American Rail
                    way Express nine fbr The Sun fund.
                    ine worm s series pinyrrs yejieruny ri-
                    u rm wun mn popmiHo, ns ititi
                    10,009 below yesterday&amp;apos;s turnout. Cold
                    aeries. drew iC2.U0 persons, and MU.B90.ro
                    the six same vtmie sot-Ciuuit series was
                    arosrtec
                    pnfw rereima Kirn hihih
                    to - day&amp;apos;s same, for the entire IBIS series
                    Game,
                    lA.t.18
                    $19,1Bft.0O
                    sioi.i.i
                    1.D19..10
                    1017 Series (Six Games).
                    Total paid attendance lSR.US.t
                    Tntnl receipts M2.VH1H.nn
                    I&amp;apos;laiers&amp;apos; share lnt,sa..n
                    Karh club&amp;apos;s share ... . HA,;oo.ai
                    National tHrnimUelon. share. . 4&amp;apos;J,SS7,SO
                    HIGH LIGHTS AND SHADOWS
                    IN ALL SPHERES OF SPORT
                    By DANIEL.
                    B&amp;apos;
                    OBTON&amp;apos;8 record In world&amp;apos;s series atlll Is Immaculate.
                    The
                    success
                    of tho Red Sox yesterday was
                    sixth triumph In tho baseball
                    been accounted for by the Red Sox and one by tho Braves. Again the
                    American League has demonstrated Us superiority In tho series over the
                    National LoaRuo and the series score now stands ten to flvo, with the gamo
                    tally flfty-slx to thirty-eight. Of ths last nine Berles eight have gone to
                    the younger organization, which sends Into the classics teams Trtilch seem
                    to bo ablo to think and act quicker than those of the senior circuit, and
                    sot m to ba better &amp;#34;money players.&amp;#34;
                    It will be noted that Boston&amp;apos;s margin yesterday again was only one
                    run. It scored every one of Its four victories over the Cubs by that ono
                    run margin. That one run seems to be Just as sacred as the cod In tho
                    Hub, for ln sixteen world&amp;apos;s series successes by Boston clubs
                    thirteen
                    havo
                    been recorded by ono run margins. In 1916 the Red Sox won&amp;apos;all their
                    four games from the Phillies by one run and dropped only one gamo to
                    the Moran forces. The series this year was the fourth In tho fifteen played
                    since 1903 that went six games. Tho other three were the 1906 series, ln
                    which tha Chicago Americans won from the Cubs, tho 1911 affair, In
                    which the Giants ran second to the Athletics, and tho 1917 competition, won
                    by the Whlto Sox over4he01ants. Six series havo been decided in flvo games.
                    Bed Sox, With Only One Error, Set Series Record.
                    In past years tho world&amp;apos;s series usually developed .mediocre
                    baseball,
                    but this season It brought out soma of the finest mechanical and mental
                    performances yet seen on any diamond In any sort of competition. The
                    Ited Sox played Ave games without an error, and their lono aajsplay was
                    a misjudged fly by Whiteman. That sets a fielding record which series to
                    come hardly will excel. Tho Cubs too, with only flvo errors, played nbove
                    world&amp;apos;s series form. The pitching was splendid and for the first
                    time
                    In
                    our
                    remembrance the series foiled to develop even ono homo run, and after
                    all tho talk of what Ruth was going to do to the fencest At that Ruth
                    brought out a threo baser which won tho fourth gamo for the Red Sox.
                    Tho catching was of a very high calibre, with the result that each club
                    stole only three bases.
                    Hooper on Four Winners; Merkle on Five Losers.
                    The series was the medium for considerable distinction for Harry
                    Hooper of tho Red Sox, for It marked his presence on the fourth winner
                    of the world&amp;apos;B title. Since&amp;apos; ho never has been on a
                    world&amp;apos;s
                    series loser ho
                    holds a place never before attained by any player. Mclnnls and Strunk
                    also achieved their fourth world&amp;apos;s scries success, but as members
                    of
                    tho
                    Athletics they suffered a defeat that surprising reversal by the Braves In
                    1914. Eddie Collins and Jack Barry also have been on four series winner,
                    but they too were on tho beaten Athletics.
                    Contrasted with Hooper&amp;apos;s record is. that of Fred Merkle, who has
                    been
                    on flvo world&amp;apos;s series losers and on nary a winner. Thrice he was
                    with
                    the Giants, once with the Superbas and now with the Cubs. If Chicago
                    is looking for the hoodoo, there he Is. However, Fred can console himself
                    with the financial return that comes even to tho losers.
                    As to the Financial &amp;#34;Failure&amp;#34; ot the Scries.
                    A great deal has been written about tho financial
                    &amp;#34;failure&amp;#34; ot
                    the
                    series this year. It Just fell short of the 130,000 mark in attendance and
                    the $180,000 mark In gato receipts. As figures go ln theso flays of con
                    crete stadiums soatlng 60,000 these may Indicate failure, but contrasted
                    with past series the 1914 classic made a good showing. Thn figures for
                    the fourteen previous series show that eight foiled to reach tho attendance
                    and flvo tho money mark reached by this year&amp;apos;s competition. WJicn
                    we
                    consider that this was a war time series and that the game had suffered
                    considerable Injury ln many ways and from many sources, the showing
                    made at the box office far exceeded expectation.&amp;#34;. John Heydler Is
                    authority
                    fur the statement that tho figures aro thousands ahead of tho National Com
                    mission&amp;apos;s advance dope.
                    Truesdell Leads Field
                    in Seniors Golf Tourney
                    Again showing their Indifference to ad -
                    vanclng years veterans o&amp;#34;t the links
                    strove to Improve on their earlier rounds
                    ln the continuation of the Seniors Golf
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1919-09-25/ed-1/seq-16/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    White Sox Defeat Browns and Thereby Capture Pennant?Yankees Get Even Break
                    Babe Ruth Hits 28th Homer,
                    Ball Clearing Roof of Stand
                    Longest Drive Ever Seen Under Shadow of Coogan&amp;apos;s
                    Bluff Ties Up Game in Ninth, but Yankees Come
                    Through With a Winning Counter in Thirteenth
                    By W. 0. McGeehan
                    Babe Ruth, of the Boston Red Sox, broke all home run records at
                    , the Polo Grounds in the ninth inning of the second game with the Yankees.
                    His twenty-eighth home run for tho season cleared the top of the right field
                    grandstand, the longest hit that was ever seen since the days when the
                    goats roamed Coogan&amp;apos;s Bluff and even before that. Numerically it
                    places
                    Ruth&amp;apos;s home run record one beyond the twenty-seven achieved by Ed
                    Williamson in 1884.
                    The blow came in the ninth inning,
                    with thfe Yanks leading by one run in
                    a tight pitching duel between young
                    Waito Hoyt and Bob Shawkey, of the
                    Yankees. Ruth had been making des?
                    perate efforts to break the record all
                    afternoon and had been swinging wild?
                    ly in his eagerness, lie was the first
                    man up. and his huge frame was
                    shaking with anxiety to swing his bat
                    on something tangible.
                    Tho first ball was high and wide,
                    and Ruth let it go by with a scowl.
                    The second one was a slow curved ball,
                    and it drifted by the port side of the
                    young giant about waist high. Every
                    ounce of the huge frame went into the
                    swing. Ho met the ball fairly, and it
                    shot toward the roof of the grandstand
                    with iuch speed that few could follow
                    its course. It cleared the roof, and
                    Ruth started to trot around the bases.
                    Ball Sails Out of Lot
                    High on the corner of the roof a
                    i:?oy who hud gone up to furl the flags,
                    waved his hands excitedly to indicate
                    that the bal i had gone out of the sta?
                    dium into the lot next door. The an?
                    nouncer ran down the field to verify
                    this&amp;apos; by word of mouth. Some years
                    back Shoeless ?loe Jackson held the
                    record for long hits at tho Polo
                    Grounds. His hit landed in the space
                    between the left field stands and the
                    bleachers. . Ruth&amp;apos;s hit went fairly out
                    of the grounds, the first time that
                    ball has been driven out of the place
                    since it was built.
                    There is no way of measuring the
                    exact distance of the hit, but the writer
                    is willing to believe that it is the long?
                    est distance ever covered by a batted
                    ball. Ruth once hit for 5t?5 feet at
                    Tampa, Fla., during a spring series.
                    Bt ing cheated out of his record by
                    Quinn in the first game seemed to
                    make the Babe more furious. He
                    whaled Bob the Gob viciously all tho
                    way. In the sixth inning he drove tho
                    ball out to the center field fence for
                    a three bagger. He was travelling so
                    rapidly in nis eagerness to turn it
                    into a home run that he emulated the
                    storied boner of Fred Merkle, for?
                    getting to touch second and was called
                    out.
                    In th&amp;#34; twelfth inning Ruth came
                    pretty close to making another home
                    run. He got another of those slow
                    curves anrb-drovo it out to far centre
                    tiold. Chicle Fewster wa? leaning
                    against the centre field wall when he
                    caught the ball. It is not good to feed
                    the Babo slow curves.
                    &amp;#34;What kind of a ball did you pitch
                    him?&amp;#34; they demanded in the press box
                    after Ruth had crowned himself king
                    and supreme monarch of all home run
                    kings.
                    &amp;#34;It was a slow curve,&amp;#34; replied Robert
                    moodily.
                    Hoyt Makes Fine Showing
                    If Ruth had not taken all of the
                    limelight in that second game and for
                    the entire afternoon, there would have
                    been another Red Sox hero worthy of
                    considerable space. The other niayer
                    is young Waito Hoyt, the boy pitcher,
                    who was first discovered by McGraw,
                    Hoyt held tho Yankees hitless for nine
                    inning- aftei they scored their first
                    run. II?&amp;apos; nat only held them hitless
                    &amp;apos;?ut he did not let a single one of therr
                    reach first base, which.is some achieve?
                    ment l&amp;apos;or a boy pitcher engaged in ?
                    pitchers&amp;apos; duel with Bob Shawkey, one
                    of the best, in the league.
                    Hoyt got I.a- first pasting in the sec?
                    ond inning. Wallie Pipp rolled one
                    down toward first and beat it to th?
                    bag, Pratt drove a long hit to left field
                    sending Pipp to third anil taking sec
                    ond on the throw-in. Duffy Lewis drove
                    one to centre and scored Pipp. The*.
                    the pitchers duel started in earnes
                    and it was the tightest sort of garni
                    until the ninth, when, as the playwrigh
                    and Ring Lanier have observed, &amp;#34;Alonj
                    came Ruth.&amp;#34;
                    Through tho twelfth itining younj
                    Waite Hoyt, with the nonchalance of i
                    veteran, continued to block the Yankee
                    otT first base. The crash came in thi
                    thirteenth. Walter Pipp came out o
                    a batting slump and drove the ball al
                    most to the ceutrefield wall. The offi
                    cia.1 traffic cop of the Yanks pullei
                    him up at third base. Pratt lifted a fl;
                    to left, field and Phipp came home, end
                    ing about as sensational a game as ha
                    been seen in the lee of Coogan&amp;apos;s Blul
                    for many a day.
                    Another sensational bit of work tha
                    gets only mild nonce in tho dazzlin
                    light of Ruth&amp;apos;s achievement was
                    throw made by Chick Fewster in th
                    tenth. Gilhooley, with one out, drov
                    a hit to deep centre. It certainl
                    looked good for a triple with a man c
                    Gilhooley&amp;apos;s speed. But Fewster fielde
                    tho ball smoothly and threw it t
                    Baker, who gol the ball on the fin
                    bound and tagged Gilhooley at tho ha?
                    Mclnnls at His Best
                    The Work of Stuffy Mel unis at fin
                    baso too would have been more tha
                    ^ prominent on any other afternooi
                    ^ Mclnnis made a couple of one-han
                    ? scoops and stops that would have mad
                    W the repulatii.il nf any other first bast
                    n,an.
                    The sartorial sensation of the aftei
                    noon was a high silk hat, about a fou
                    quart ha&amp;apos;, which made its way into th
                    press box after the start of the secon
                    game. It adorned the head of Eddi
                    Gorman, the old battler who formerl
                    was associated with the late .lohn ]
                    Sullivan. Tin? hat was attended by
                    frock coat and a white carnation. A
                    first tha i! iwd was sania what pu/.zlei
                    They did not know whether the weare
                    was a rich rolling mill worker como t
                    buy the Yanks or an undertaker com
                    to bury them.
                    Hey Broun, who frequently is panne
                    by disgruntled hams because he use
                    to eke out an existence writing basi
                    ball, should have been on deck to sc
                    that baseball writers sometimes ai
                    permitted to associate with four-tiuai
                    liais and other refining mtluences. M
                    Gorman apologized for the apparei
                    ?t&amp;apos;stvjitatioustiess. He said that ho ha
                    to attend an early wake with Sai
                    (&amp;apos;rant* and had to come to the par
                    dressed in order to bo there in tim
                    Mr. Gorman prides himself on h
                    punctuality and punctiliousness in th
                    matter of wakes.
                    In the first game Murderers&amp;apos; Row, t
                    the Yankees, ate out of the hands t
                    Sammy Jones in the pinches. Thn
                    times the Yatiks had the bases tillei
                    but&amp;apos; could not punch a single ru
                    across. In all fourteen Yanks pet
                    ?lively perished on tho paths. The
                    g&amp;apos;jt nine bases on balls and two me
                    were helped to first by errors.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1919-11-01/ed-1/seq-20/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text> Georsre Herman Ruth, better known as Battering Babe Ruth, prin ipai slugger
                    in major league baseball these day?, has recently given ha world an insight into
                    his peculiar brain procesa?if you will admit e possesses a brain. Incidentally,
                    hie speech shows him to be quite in ccord with many others who think little of
                    their plighted faith. Though ;? has two more years to complet? his contract
                    ?with the Boston Red ex at a salary of $10,000 yearly. Ruth would sign a new one
                    calling ?7T $20,000 yearly. Furthermore, he says he will not play with the Boe
                    ra club unless his wishes are granted. . Last spring Ruth held out until the
                    last minute. He wanted a alary of $15,000, if our memory be correct, but finally
                    compromised by ?ft?ing a three-year-contract calling for a salary of $10,000
                    yearly. All oat took place before he began hammering home runs until he had
                    Token ail previous big league records for this stunt. He admitted that e was
                    satisfied with the treatment given him by both Harry Frazee and Jd Barrow. He
                    proved it by playing fine ball all season. But Babe has &amp;apos;?gtened to
                    -erpent
                    tongues. Now he would quit playing ball unless the ?oston club agrees to make a
                    new contract calling for $20,000 a year. The Joke of the sltuatioa is that tarry
                    Frasee la In pretty much of a &amp;#34; ? He has established a precedent W
                    Ruth
                    to
                    follow by trading Carl is;, s to the New Tork club when the ubmarine funger grew
                    tired of iking along with a losing club. So ar as Frasee ia concerned, he has
                    ittlc argument to offer Ruth when &amp;apos;Bey ?ret together for a
                    conference
                    ?garehng this contract matter But ni? doesn&amp;apos;t absolve Ruth, just
                    the
                    ?am?
                    ?y contract with the Boston club an t worth a dime,&amp;apos;&amp;apos;
                    Maya
                    told some
                    Sew York baaeball writers &amp;#34;I&amp;apos;m go :ag to tear ?t up and
                    demand
                    $20 (XX)
                    for next year. If I don&amp;apos;t get that ftsrure. I shall refuse to play
                    ball
                    and
                    &amp;apos;he Boston club will have to sell my rei aase &amp;#34;Mays had
                    a
                    contract for
                    three rears, but he made the Boston club *ei: him to the Yankees. Be Just luit
                    the Red Sox and went home. If stave can get away with that kind of ?tuff you bet
                    I can do the same. teatrate?. I? IlietgaL Tee, I signed for three years Last
                    ??Bring but my contract contains the ten days&amp;apos; release clause,
                    which
                    makes
                    ?t Illegal. If I lost an arm or a leg. &amp;apos;hey could let me go and I
                    couldn&amp;apos;t ?ret the rest of this salary.
                    &amp;#34;I&amp;apos;m the best
                    drawing card
                    in the mtne no? Ty Cobb&amp;apos;s salary is *r20 000 ? y??ar and I intend
                    to
                    net
                    the ?ame money. You can say for me hat I shall not put on a Boston uni form next
                    year if I don&amp;apos;t receive just JO ?WO Iron ma.&amp;#34; This must
                    be
                    great
                    reading for those misguided fools in Boston who presented Battering Babe with a
                    $500 diamoci at the close of the season a? an appreciation of his great work for
                    the city. Some day the fans will a-et the rieht angle on what profes sional ball
                    players think of them. Then they&amp;apos;ll cot out all those foolish
                    pr?seentations of traveling bags, suits of clothes and diamond stick pins. not
                    to speak of watches and charms. The players take them-?sure, why not. but they
                    always have a laugh at the expense of the poor boobs who oaughed up their coin
                    for the present. Ty ?bb niaarree?.
                    Ty Cobb. who has had several
                    tiffs with the Detroit club regarding
                    the proper ?mount of salary he should
                    draw, disagrees with Ruth tn the
                    situation now faon?? the ponderous
                    slugger Ty believes that a player is
                    eetitled to all he can get from his
                    club
                    &amp;#34;But.** aays the Detroit veteran
                    outfielder, &amp;#34;once a player signs a ;
                    contract h? Is in honor bound to do ?
                    SF
                    HORNING
                    LOANS
                    On DiaunoiscU, Watizh?**??
                    *ad Jeweiry
                    (South of Highway Bridge)
                    JCIUUI ??????
                    ??? a-UCXt&amp;#34;.
                    ?IVa-Xi rfclKHJS.
                    Tafea ?*?**? ?* &amp;#34;?h ??- aad PvauseyV
                    -rnktr erw. tmr ea?-sth ?*a? ?( ~
                    M ?ata sv ??are Am ?ask wem.
                    hl? level beat on the field until his
                    engagement expires. A player In
                    midseason has no moral or legal
                    right to become dissatisfied with the
                    terms of the agreement to which h?
                    haa attached hia signatura. He
                    must give the best be has to his
                    owner That is the way to look at
                    this matter, and 1 have no sympa
                    thy at all for Mays or any other
                    player who acts like him.&amp;#34;
                    Ty Cohb ia Judging from his
                    words, an honorable man. as well as
                    brainy. He believes In sticking to
                    his agreements. He very likely
                    knows, too. that if&amp;apos;contracts are to
                    be torn up at the whim of a player,
                    the professional game is going to
                    perish, ending once and for all the
                    opportunities of all players to
                    make a living at it.
                    Heads Like Taefcs.
                    The fact is that most professional
                    ball players have heads like tacks,
                    lacking space for brains. Every now
                    and then something happens that
                    proves this?Babe; Ruth&amp;apos;s statement is
                    the latest.
                    Baseball writers, when talking
                    among themselves, are ever classify
                    ing this player and that as either &amp;#34;a
                    skull&amp;#34; or not. &amp;#34;A skull&amp;#34; is an ex
                    ample of pure and unsullied ivory in
                    the cranium. And the fans vsjould be
                    amazed were they to get the inside
                    stuff relative to many of their heroes.
                    In the sport columns players are al
                    ways being quoted, but seldom if ever
                    are their literal words used. All
                    newspapers ban certain forms of
                    language, which are used by most
                    players. Most newspapers require
                    their writers to use plain and correct
                    English. Many players use plain
                    English, but it&amp;apos;s not always correct.
                    The sports writers make them won
                    ders to the fans when, as a matter of
                    facL they&amp;apos;re &amp;#34;skulls.&amp;#34;
                    Serte? Offen? ? fase..
                    The annual world&amp;apos;s serle? Jamboree
                    proves yearly Just what has been
                    written above. You know those &amp;#34;ex
                    pert?&amp;apos;&amp;#34; whose names appear over col
                    umns and columns of stuff about the
                    big series? Well, one in a million ac
                    tually write their stuff. To our own
                    knowledge. Eddie Collins is alone of
                    all the &amp;#34;experts&amp;#34; who ever wrote the
                    stuff appearing under his signature
                    There may be others! but we* don&amp;apos;t
                    know it.
                    &amp;apos;Way back in 1000 we asked Eddie
                    Collins to &amp;#34;write&amp;#34; for our columns a
                    certain story. No. It wasn&amp;apos;t for The
                    Washington Times. It wasn&amp;apos;t for a
                    paperin this city. We expected him
                    to come in. talk a bit, give us his
                    ideas, and then watch us write it.
                    But nothing like that. In he did
                    com?, but bringing with him his story
                    written in sn excellent hand. He
                    apologised for not having a type
                    writer His English was perfect. He
                    seemed to know how to say exactly
                    what he wanted to say.
                    It was such a surpris? that we put
                    on our hat and hied ourself to th*
                    nearest place for a couple of quick
                    ones. The shock was almost fataL
                    Unknown, trained newspaper men
                    write all those ream? of Junk usually
                    credited to tb? diamond atara. That&amp;apos;?
                    wj?y w. did not Inflict upon Washing
                    ton fan? a ?tory of &amp;#34;How to Make
                    Home Runs, by Babe Ruth.&amp;#34; when it
                    wg? offered some weeks ago W?
                    knew Juet about how much of It he
                    could dig out in ten years Hi? latest
                    statement &amp;apos;increase? our respect for
                    oar own perspicacity.
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1919-12-03/ed-1/seq-21/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Babe Ruth to Seek
                    Jack Dempsey&amp;apos;s Crown
                    LOS ANGELES, Dec. 2. It was
                    announced to-day that Babo
                    Buth, home run record holder,
                    May become a professional boxer.
                    &amp;#34;Kid&amp;#34; McCoy, a former pugilist, and
                    Al St. John, a motion picture actor,
                    to-day entered into an agreement by
                    which McCoy will train Ruth for
                    thirty days and if his report was fa
                    vorable St John would finance a
                    campaign of the outfielder to obtain
                    a match with Jack Dempsey, heavy-,
                    woight champion.
                    Ruth has given up plans to become
                    a motion picture actor. Tho home
                    run champion satd ho used to be In
                    preliminary boxing contests In Bal
                    timore when ho was a mere boy.
                    &amp;#34;I always have wanted to be a pro
                    fessional boxer,&amp;#34; said &amp;#34;Ruth to-night,
                    &amp;#34;but I gave up any future I might
                    have had in that game to play base
                    ball If McCoy and St. John think
                    I have any future, t am willing to
                    do everything they ask.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1920-01-06/ed-1/seq-8/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>BABE RUTH PURCHASED BY YANKEES FROM RED SOX FOR $125,000?OTHER SPORTj
                    Yankees Buy Babe Ruth
                    From Boston for $125,000
                    Manhattan Tribe Purchase Home Run Slug
                    ger From Hub City Team in Biggest Deal
                    In History of Baseball.
                    Boston, Jan. 5.?&amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth, world champion home-run
                    player
                    of the Red Sox, has been bought by the New York Yankees, ac
                    cording to an announcement made tonight. Harry H. Frazee, owner
                    of the Red Sox, who told of the sale of Ruth, declined to name the
                    price paid, but declared it was larger than had ever before been paid.
                    The deal was said to have involved no other players.
                    Estimates, unofficial, but said to have been based upon &amp;#34;inside
                    information,&amp;#34; placed the figure at which
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth was
                    told at
                    ,the unprecedented sum of $125,000. Efforts to have this estimate
                    substantiated or denied failed, but it was generally reported that the
                    figure was not far from correct.
                    Highest Figure Yet Paid.
                    If the estimate proves accurate, the sale of Ruth not only ele
                    vates the trading of baseball players to inclusion in the category of
                    sugar, shoes, clothing and other high-priced necessities, but records
                    a sale at more than double the highest price heretofore paid for
                    a player.
                    When Alexander and Killifer were traded from Philadelphia to
                    Chicago, $55,000 changed hands. The greatest price paid for a single
                    player up to the trading of Ruth was said to have been the $50,000
                    given for Tris Speaker when he went from the Red Sox to Cleveland.
                    Richardson Is Here for
                    Meeting of Stockholders
                    William II. Richardson, vie? pres
                    ident and treasurer of the local base
                    ball club, arrived in the city last
                    night to attend the meeting of the
                    board of directors of the Washing
                    ton baseball club to be held at noon
                    today.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1920-08-22/ed-1/seq-53/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Did Babe Ruth Get Another One To-day?&amp;#34; | Not &amp;#34;How Did
                    the Game
                    Come
                    Out?&amp;#34; *| Now the Great American Question 4 By W? O. McGeehan IF THE
                    lata
                    lamented Shakes? peare were a&amp;apos; baseball writer he might usa a line
                    that
                    he
                    wested upon some more or less obscure hero of antiquity and say of
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth, &amp;#34;He doth bestride the narrow
                    baseball
                    fields like a
                    Colos? sus.&amp;#34; For &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth is Hercules and
                    Thor
                    reincarnated, the
                    Colossus of Swat. His bat is the club of Hercules and the hammer of Thor, the
                    symbol of sheer, primitive might before which the puny folk bow and offer
                    worship. But for the game of baseball, the youngest game of the youngest peo?
                    ple, George Herman Ruth, the &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth who dwarfs all
                    other
                    personalities in the daily news, might have been a peaceful cigar maker or
                    perhaps a third-rate heavyweight pugilist instead of the national idol of the
                    American people. The &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; was Fortune&amp;apos;s
                    dar? ling,
                    though Fortune
                    concealed her great and kindly intentions as far as he was concerned when the
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; was 2. boy. For the
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; was born
                    left-hander!.
                    Hercules was a right-hander. Thor never was pic? tured as wielding his hammer
                    from the port side. None of the heroes of antiquity, as far as can be ascer?
                    tained, was a southpaw. Harry Leon Wilson was the first novelist to put a
                    left-hander in the near-hero class, and he i ;d it in a half-hearted
                    fashion.
                    Moreover, little George Herman
                    Ruth was a half-orphan at a very
                    early age and was sent to an insti?
                    tution for orphans. He was nearly
                    an orphan boy, and, according to
                    the San ford and Merton books, he
                    should have taken a morbid sort of
                    point of view at an early age and
                    learned something useful. But the
                    youth of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth was applied
                    mostly to the study of the great
                    American game of baseball.
                    You are not going to draw any
                    conventional moral from the early
                    boyhood of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth. He was
                    not a particularly industrious or
                    thrifty lad, chockful of conventional
                    virtues. He was just a normal,
                    chuckle-headed combination of Tom
                    Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn. He
                    Was Just natural and just human.
                    FORTUNATELY the boyhood of
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth was intrusted to
                    men who understand human
                    nature, and particularly the human
                    boy?the Christian Brothers, of Bal?
                    timore. The fraternity is not limited
                    to Baltimore. It is all over the
                    *orld. It is made up of big-hearted
                    ?fcn. consecrated to the work of mak
                    lfig men out of the raw material.
                    They had charge of the bringing
                    UP of George Herman Ruth and
                    &amp;apos;hey have turned over to the world
                    ??Colossus of Swat. It is due to
                    th*ir human understanding that
                    George Herman Ruth was not
                    wwarted and turned aside into more
                    Wo**ic iine8 0f encjeavor,
                    U?Kt lanatiQ than ?sqr *rf fbe
                    I boy romances of Tattered Tom and
                    Ragged Dick, by Horatio Alger jr.
                    ; is the rise of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth. The Al-,
                    | ger heroes became mere bankers or
                    traction magnates, but George Her
                    | man Ruth, the waif of Baltimore, be?
                    came &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth, at whose shrine
                    &amp;apos; bankers and traction magnates burn
                    incense. Ever and anon these jaded
                    near-successes pick up the tape, not
                    to see the condition of the market,
                    but to learn whether the latest is the
                    forty-fifth or forty-sixth home run
                    ! knocked out by the &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; for the
                    I season.
                    And these heroes envy &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34;
                    ! Ruth the left-handed, the boy who
                    ! was regarded as far from bright in
                    ;his classes. For the &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; can hit
                    them out with the joyous freedom of
                    Hei-culcs swinging his club or Thor
                    throwing his hammer through the&amp;apos;
                    clouds. All the tricks of the pitchers
                    are vain when he faces them, and all
                    the walls of the baseball parks are
                    lowered when his bat crashes against
                    the baseball. Homer would have
                    loved him if the blind singer had had
                    a season pass to the Polo Grounds.
                    THAT Ruth is the greatest bat?
                    ter of them all is admitted by
                    two members of the old Orioles;
                    and when two members of the old
                    Orioles agree upon anything, that
                    makes it official and irrefutable. If
                    there is anybody so ignorant of im?
                    portant American history that he
                    does not know who the old Orioles
                    are, we will explain, more in pity
                    than in indignation, that the old
                    Orioles were members of the great?
                    est baseball team of a generation or
                    so ago.
                    The two Orioles who made the ad?
                    mission that &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth was the
                    greatest baseball player in the whole
                    world are Wilbert Robinson, mana?
                    ger of the Brooklyn National League
                    baseball team, and Joseph Kelly,
                    scout for the Yankees. Both of these
                    gentlemen are grandfathers and citi?
                    zens of high repute in the city where
                    they dwell, which also happens to i
                    be the home of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth. &amp;#34;Wil-1
                    bert Robinson was a catcher, and still
                    ; holds the world&amp;apos;s record for consecu?
                    tive base hits in one game. Joseph
                    Kelly was an outfielder of sorts on
                    the old Orioles, and his present oc-1
                    cupation is &amp;#34;ivory hunting,&amp;#34; looking
                    upon baseball playera and appraising
                    them ?at their true > jrtb to their
                    employers and to the national pas?
                    time.
                    These two authorities admitted&amp;#34; to
                    me in th? presence of witnesses that
                    never, even in the days of the old
                    Orioles, was there a baseball player
                    who could hit like &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth. Con?
                    sider the importance of this admis?
                    sion. The members of the old Ori?
                    oles are the most conservative per?
                    sons in th vorld. Never before
                    have they au. : ..ed that any player
                    of the present was anywhere near as
                    wonderful as tl\e players of their
                    glorious day.
                    &amp;#34;He can hit them harder than any?
                    body, and he can hit them oftener,&amp;#34;
                    they admitted from the fullness of
                    their hearts. They did not qualify
                    the statement, They did ?ob assert
                    that the pitchers were less canny
                    and that the ball parks were smaller.
                    They admitted that the heroes of
                    their day were lost in the shadow of
                    the Colossus of Swat. They admitted
                    that even in the days when the old
                    Orioles were young &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth
                    would have loomed up above them
                    all.
                    That Ruth broke all big league
                    records for home run getting last
                    year is in the book. That he has
                    broken his own record this year and
                    is on the way to setting a mark far
                    beyond the misty horizons ?if the
                    baseball world is l?o\vn. But the
                    old Orioles have explained away the
                    performances of other more modern
                    heroes of baseball. Ruth&amp;apos;s achieve?
                    ments they Jrott ungrudgingly.,
                    That is almost as marvelous as the
                    achievements themselves.
                    .
                    ONCE upon a time the youth of
                    this land worshiped another
                    young giant, a right-hander
                    and an exponent of another and el?
                    der sport?John L. Sullivan. The
                    right arm of John L. ?Sullivan was
                    mighty in its day, but the left arm i
                    of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth is mightier in its I
                    day and generation in the matter of
                    sheer numbers of worshipers.
                    | They used to block the corridors
                    of the hotels, and even the streets,1
                    ? to see the mighty John L. pass. They
                    do that in the case of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth,
                    I too. It is not for me to disparage
                    | the memory of John L. Sullivan, the
                    | gladiator, in th? days-cf hi? greatest
                    -?
                    ring glory, but I think, that his ad?
                    mirers saw that particular John L.
                    through rose glasses and that they
                    worshiped an illusion.
                    The John L. Sullivan of the later !
                    day, the John L. who beat down his ?
                    own worst enemy and lifted up his ;
                    self-respect from the muck, was the
                    John L. that should have been wor- ;
                    shiped, for that John L. Sullivan :
                    was a mighty gladiator. The John ,
                    L. Sullivan who knocked out ring an- j
                    tagonists with a right-hand punch to j
                    the jaw was a mere mass of brawn ?
                    and muscle, but the gray and fat old |
                    John L. who conquered himself was i
                    the true fighter.
                    But we are considering the John L.
                    that was the popular idol, the &amp;apos;
                    brawny man who was followed by &amp;apos;
                    the men and the boys and cheered
                    when he stalked abroad. He was !
                    not a particularly affable character.
                    This big &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth is a far
                    more likable person. He is full of i
                    good nature and the joy of living.
                    He is a modest enough young man, :
                    and he knows his limitations, though ;
                    he acknowledges no limitations as j
                    far as the baseball diamonds and j
                    the fences around them are con
                    cerned. He is not falsely modest to
                    the point of affectation, for he has
                    that supreme confidence in himself
                    that comes after certain achievement.
                    But he will not play to the gallery
                    consciously. He likes the gallery
                    and he understands it, and he likes
                    to have it understand him. ?
                    Ruth is, perhaps, too simple, or
                    it may be too wise, to try to fool his
                    gallery, as other stars of his own ;
                    game or stars in other lines of en?
                    deavor have tried to do in vain. For
                    nobody can fool his gallery. No
                    truly wise man ever tried.
                    THE best judges of a man ar?
                    the men with whom he works !
                    or with whom he plays.
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth, naturally, is the high?
                    est salaried ballplayer on the New
                    York Yankees. He might, if he were
                    like some of the stars of baseball or i
                    stars of some of the arts, claim all
                    the privileges of a star and hold
                    himself aloof from his fellow players.
                    Here again is the simplicity or the
                    wisdom of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth. He plays
                    the game with the team and for the
                    team, and the men &amp;apos; he plays with
                    know it and appreciate it. &amp;#34;Babe&amp;apos;
                    Ruth will even make the &amp;#34;college
                    try&amp;#34; to get a base on an impossible
                    chance. The &amp;#34;cdllege try&amp;#34; is the vet?
                    eran professional&amp;apos;s term of contempt
                    for zealous endeavor that seems fu?
                    tile on the facts of it.
                    _ an the &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; *nake?th? two
                    owners of the Yankees, Colonels I
                    Ruppert and Huston, shudder with !
                    apprehension when he hurls himself
                    against a wall to get a fly ball, or I
                    when he throws his huge bulk
                    through the air in the effort to steal i
                    a base. They rejoice in his spirit
                    and his wholehearted way of play?
                    ing, but at the same time they per?
                    spire with apprehension lest some?
                    thing should happen that would de?
                    prive them of the most expensive in?
                    vestment in professional baseball.
                    Some stars have disrupted base?
                    ball teams, rousing jealousies, but
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth, admittedly the great?
                    est star of them all, has made the
                    Yankees a team. The advent of the
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; has brought them the chance
                    of that &amp;#34;world&amp;apos;s scries dough,&amp;#34; which
                    should be something like $7,000 a
                    player. It has also made them the
                    team of the big leagues. They do not
                    begrudge the &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; the homage
                    that is paid him. As far as Ruth
                    is concerned, there is no professional
                    jealousy on the Yankee team.
                    Just to what extent the present
                    prosperity of professional baseball
                    is due to &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth I would not
                    care to say, but it is considerable
                    When I first trailed West with tht
                    Yankees, they told me in Chicagc
                    that there had been little or no in
                    tereat in the Chicago White Sox. Bu
                    I when the Yankees came ta Cbicagi
                    they turned out to the extent of 20,
                    000 a day and upward to see the
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; &amp;#34;bust one.&amp;#34;
                    Once, with the score 2 to 1 in the
                    eighth and a tense pitchers&amp;apos; duelen,
                    the Chicago pitcher passed &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34;
                    Ruth. Ten thousand people started
                    to walk out of Comiskey Park.
                    There remained yet the chance of
                    the melodramatic ninth inning rally,
                    but the ten thousand had lost all
                    interest in the game for the after?
                    noon. It was clear thatr they were
                    not going to see &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth knock
                    a home run, and nothing else mat?
                    tered.
                    Civic pride, inter-city rivalry, in?
                    terest in the national game were
                    minor considerations. The &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34;
                    was not due to &amp;#34;bust one.&amp;#34;
                    IN CLEVELAND 1 was talking
                    to two tired business men early
                    in the afternoon.
                    Said one of them gravely:
                    &amp;#34;This &amp;apos;Babe&amp;apos; Ruth is a menace. He
                    is responsible to a large degree for
                    i the lack of production in these
                    : manufacturing towns around the
                    Lakes. Go out to the ball park to?
                    day and you will see thousands of
                    young men taking the afternoon off
                    just to see &amp;apos;Babe&amp;apos; Ruth &amp;apos;bust
                    one.&amp;apos;
                    i It is really quite serious. What are</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1963-11-17/ed-1/seq-135/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Russell and the great Babe
                    Ruth pose at opening
                    day ceremonies at Yankee
                    Stadium. Russell
                    threw open the gates to let in
                    the first fans.
                    7

                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1920-08-22/ed-1/seq-53/ocr/</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>&amp;#34;Did Babe Ruth Get Another One To-day?&amp;#34; | Not
                    &amp;#34;How Did
                    the Game
                    Come Out?&amp;#34; *| Now the Great American Question 4 By W? O. McGeehan IF
                    THE
                    lata lamented Shakes? peare were a&amp;apos; baseball writer he might usa a
                    line
                    that he wested upon some more or less obscure hero of antiquity and say of
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth, &amp;#34;He doth bestride the narrow
                    baseball
                    fields like a
                    Colos? sus.&amp;#34; For &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth is Hercules and
                    Thor
                    reincarnated, the
                    Colossus of Swat. His bat is the club of Hercules and the hammer of Thor, the
                    symbol of sheer, primitive might before which the puny folk bow and offer
                    worship. But for the game of baseball, the youngest game of the youngest peo?
                    ple, George Herman Ruth, the &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth who dwarfs all
                    other
                    personalities in the daily news, might have been a peaceful cigar maker or
                    perhaps a third-rate heavyweight pugilist instead of the national idol of the
                    American people. The &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; was Fortune&amp;apos;s
                    dar? ling,
                    though Fortune
                    concealed her great and kindly intentions as far as he was concerned when the
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; was 2. boy. For the
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; was born
                    left-hander!.
                    Hercules was a right-hander. Thor never was pic? tured as wielding his hammer
                    from the port side. None of the heroes of antiquity, as far as can be ascer?
                    tained, was a southpaw. Harry Leon Wilson was the first novelist to put a
                    left-hander in the near-hero class, and he i ;d it in a half-hearted
                    fashion.
                    Moreover, little George Herman
                    Ruth was a half-orphan at a very
                    early age and was sent to an insti?
                    tution for orphans. He was nearly
                    an orphan boy, and, according to
                    the San ford and Merton books, he
                    should have taken a morbid sort of
                    point of view at an early age and
                    learned something useful. But the
                    youth of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth was applied
                    mostly to the study of the great
                    American game of baseball.
                    You are not going to draw any
                    conventional moral from the early
                    boyhood of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth. He was
                    not a particularly industrious or
                    thrifty lad, chockful of conventional
                    virtues. He was just a normal,
                    chuckle-headed combination of Tom
                    Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn. He
                    Was Just natural and just human.
                    FORTUNATELY the boyhood of
                    &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth was intrusted to
                    men who understand human
                    nature, and particularly the human
                    boy?the Christian Brothers, of Bal?
                    timore. The fraternity is not limited
                    to Baltimore. It is all over the
                    *orld. It is made up of big-hearted
                    ?fcn. consecrated to the work of mak
                    lfig men out of the raw material.
                    They had charge of the bringing
                    UP of George Herman Ruth and
                    &amp;apos;hey have turned over to the world
                    ??Colossus of Swat. It is due to
                    th*ir human understanding that
                    George Herman Ruth was not
                    wwarted and turned aside into more
                    Wo**ic iine8 0f encjeavor,
                    U?Kt lanaiQ than ?sqr *rf fbe
                    I boy romances of Tattered Tom and
                    Ragged Dick, by Horatio Alger jr.
                    ; is the rise of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth. The Al-,
                    | ger heroes became mere bankers or
                    traction magnates, but George Her
                    | man Ruth, the waif of Baltimore, be?
                    came &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth, at whose shrine
                    &amp;apos; bankers and traction magnates burn
                    incense. Ever and anon these jaded
                    near-successes pick up the tape, not
                    to see the condition of the market,
                    but to learn whether the latest is the
                    forty-fifth or forty-sixth home run
                    ! knocked out by the &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; for the
                    I season.
                    And these heroes envy &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34;
                    ! Ruth the left-handed, the boy who
                    ! was regarded as far from bright in
                    ;his classes. For the &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; can hit
                    them out with the joyous freedom of
                    Hei-culcs swinging his club or Thor
                    throwing his hammer through the&amp;apos;
                    clouds. All the tricks of the pitchers
                    are vain when he faces them, and all
                    the walls of the baseball parks are
                    lowered when his bat crashes against
                    the baseball. Homer would have
                    loved him if the blind singer had had
                    a season pass to the Polo Grounds.
                    THAT Ruth is the greatest bat?
                    ter of them all is admitted by
                    two members of the old Orioles;
                    and when two members of the old
                    Orioles agree upon anything, that
                    makes it official and irrefutable. If
                    there is anybody so ignorant of im?
                    portant American history that he
                    does not know who the old Orioles
                    are, we will explain, more in pity
                    than in indignation, that the old
                    Orioles were members of the great?
                    est baseball team of a generation or
                    so ago.
                    The two Orioles who made the ad?
                    mission that &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth was the
                    greatest baseball player in the whole
                    world are Wilbert Robinson, mana?
                    ger of the Brooklyn National League
                    baseball team, and Joseph Kelly,
                    scout for the Yankees. Both of these
                    gentlemen are grandfathers and citi?
                    zens of high repute in the city where
                    they dwell, which also happens to i
                    be the home of &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth. &amp;#34;Wil-1
                    bert Robinson was a catcher, and still
                    ; holds the world&amp;apos;s record for consecu?
                    tive base hits in one game. Joseph
                    Kelly was an outfielder of sorts on
                    the old Orioles, and his present oc-1
                    cupation is &amp;#34;ivory hunting,&amp;#34; looking
                    upon baseball playera and appraising
                    them ?at their true > jrtb to their
                    employers and to the national pas?
                    time.
                    These two authorities admitted&amp;#34; to
                    me in th? presence of witnesses that
                    never, even in the days of the old
                    Orioles, was there a baseball player
                    who could hit like &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth. Con?
                    sider the importance of this admis?
                    sion. The members of the old Ori?
                    oles are the most conservative per?
                    sons in th vorld. Never before
                    have they au. : ..ed that any player
                    of the present was anywhere near as
                    wonderful as tl\e players of their
                    glorious day.
                    &amp;#34;He can hit them harder than any?
                    body, and he can hit them oftener,&amp;#34;
                    they admitted from the fullness of
                    their hearts. They did not qualify
                    the statement, They did ?ob assert
                    that the pitchers were less canny
                    and that the ball parks were smaller.
                    They admitted that the heroes of
                    their day were lost in the shadow of
                    the Colossus of Swat. They admitted
                    that even in the days when the old
                    Orioles were young &amp;#34;Babe&amp;#34; Ruth
                    would have loomed up above them
                    all.
                    That Ruth broke all big league
                    records for home run getting last
                    year is in the book. That he has
                    broken his own record this year and
                    is on the way to setting a mark far
                    beyond the misty horizons ?if the
                    baseball world is l?o\vn. But the
                    old Orioles have explained away the
                    performances of other more modern
                    heroes of baseball. Ruth&amp;apos;s achieve?
                    ments they Jrott ungrudgingly.,
                    That is almost as marvelous as the
                    achievements themselves.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045389/1920-07-18/ed-1/seq-49/ocr/</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85047513/1963-08-29/ed-1/seq-15/#date1=1756&amp;index=2&amp;rows=20&amp;words=BABE+Babe+Ruth+RUTH&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=Babe+Ruth&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1922-07-09/ed-1/seq-64/ocr</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1935-09-29/ed-1/seq-97/#date1=1756&amp;index=0&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Babe+Ruth&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=Babe+Ruth&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
    <topic>
        <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-mothers-day</id>
        <results>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1912-05-11/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.294,-0.079,1.589,1.589,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Sons and Daughters Unite to
                    Commemorate Mothers'
                    Day in the City
                    How many of the Juniors have
                    heard of JMiss Annie Jarvis?
                    She is the Avoman who brought
                    about the establishment of a
                    "mothers' day" in almost every
                    stale in the union, not to mention
                    the nations of the world and
                    whose indefatigable efforts have
                    served to arouse in every man,
                    woman and child a sense of the
                    beauty of motherhood and the
                    duty we owe to our mothers.
                    Miss Jarvis is a Philadelphia
                    woman. A few years ago, alone
                    and unaided she started the
                    "mothers' day" movement, and so
                    eloquent was her plea that the
                    idea found instant and hearty ac
                    ceptance. Since then the plan has
                    been gaining ground and within
                    the last four years the setting
                    aside of a mothers' day has been
                    accepted and indorsed by nearly
                    every governor in the union and
                    many of the crowned heads of Eu
                    rope.
                    "Mothers' day" falls on the sec
                    ond Sunday of May.
                    Tomorrow is the day when the
                    Junior boys and girls pay special
                    court to mother. On all the other
                    holidays, remember, mother pays
                    special attention to you, but on
                    the second Sunday in May condi
                    tions are reversed a bit and moth
                    er comes in for the lion's share
                    of pleasures.
                    See if you can't do something
                    especially nice for her tomorrow.
                    Show her how much you care for
                    her and how very dear she is to
                    you. Help.her with the work
                    around the house, wait on her for
                    a change and give her the benefit
                    of her holiday.
                    "Mothers* day" will be celebrat
                    ed in many of the churches tomor**
                    row, but that is not enough, boys
                    and girls. It should be celebrated
                    in your hearts as well. There is
                    no one in all the world who will
                    do as much for you as will your
                    mother. When every one else has
                    forsaken you and you haven't a
                    friend on earth, your mother will
                    stand by you with words of en
                    couragement and love.
                    See if you can't make her to
                    morrow a very pleasant one in
                    deed.
                    The white carnation has been
                    chosen as the flower symbolical
                    of filial devotion and the florists
                    are crowding their windows with
                    the beautiful emblems of purity
                    and love, for everyone's going to
                    make a big bow to mother tomor
                    row.
                    Don't forget to wear a white
                    carnation and wish mother the
                    happiest returns of the day.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063381/1912-05-11/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.233,-0.073,1.466,1.466,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>
                    "White flower for Mother dead
                    Bright flower for Mother living
                    It was five years ago that Miss An-
                    na Jarvis, of Philadelphia, con-
                    ceived the idea of selecting one day
                    of the year upon which the devotion
                    to mothers' memory should be ob-
                    served, and the second Sunday in
                    May being the day upon which fell
                    the anniversary of her mother's
                    death, that day was chosen by her as
                    Mothers' day.
                    Miss Jarvis wrote to churches, so-
                    cieties, public officials, noted people
                    and the press and all joined in the
                    movement which she had originated
                    It has spread so rapidly that this
                    year a majority of the governors of
                    states have issued proclamations set-
                    ting aside tomorrow as Mothers' day
                    and suggesting that it be made one of
                    the state's memorial days.
                    The original plan was that each
                    one wishing to honor his mother
                    would wear a white carnation, but
                    the demand proving greater than the
                    supply, it was decided to wear a
                    white carnation for the dead and a
                    bright flower for the living So wear
                    a flower tomorrow, white or bright,
                    "in honor of the best mother in the
                    world, your mother."
                    The Nymore Road.
                    At the railroad and warehouse com-
                    mission hearing yesterday at Nymore,
                    one fact stood out with startling dis-
                    tinctness ^Every witness examined
                    for Nymore testified that because of
                    the j?oad between Nymore and Be-
                    midji, loads coming to Bemidjl from
                    IMHk Wl
                    the country south and east of Ny-
                    more had to be cut in two at Nymore
                    and two trips made to coVer the last
                    mile
                    It is because of this condition,
                    more than any other, that the people
                    of Nymore are asking the commission
                    to order a depot or depots built by
                    the railroads A depot at Nymore
                    will be a body blow to Bemidjl, as
                    it will cut oft a tonnage revenue of
                    about $10,000 a year, but if the com-
                    mission orders one, Bemidji has only
                    itself to blame The road should
                    have been put in hist class shape
                    long ago as it is one of the main
                    traffic arteries to this city
                    Foitunately for Bemidjl, the com-
                    mission was taken to Nymore over
                    the railroad tracks If it had been
                    en over the road itself, it might
                    have given a decision on the spot
                    At any rate, whether or not the depot
                    is ordered, the road should be put in
                    first-class shape at once
                    The Commercial club committee on
                    highways was instructed last Tues-
                    day night to prepare figures on the
                    cost of paving the Nymore road
                    These, with figures on the cost of
                    making a sand or macadam road, are
                    to be presented to the city council at
                    its next meeting For several years
                    past $150 to $200 per year has been
                    spent on this road and it is nof much
                    better today than when Chief Bemid*
                    ji lived on the lake shore
                    Not only the people at Nymore are
                    asking for this depot, but the farmers
                    living out in that country who have
                    to use this road want better shipping
                    facilities A paved street from Be-
                    midji to Nymore would remedy the
                    condition and remove a good cause
                    for complaint
                </text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1914-05-07/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.174,-0.067,1.349,1.349,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>MISS ANNA JARVIS,
                    Philadelphia woman, who originated
                    "Mothers' Day," and secured national
                    recognition for it.
                    MRS
                    .U
                    I
                    SPEAKER AT GUILD
                    Miss Mabel T. Boardman Also
                    on Program at National
                    Convention.
                    LONDON, May 7. The woman's suf
                    frago bill was rejected last night by the
                    house of lords by a vote of 1M to 60.
                    Speeches in favor of tho bill were
                    made by Baron Courtney, of Penwlth.
                    the Earl of Lytton. and Baron Wll
                    loughby de Broke, whllo Baron Wear-,
                    dale, the Marquis of Crowe, and Vis
                    count St. Aldwyn spoke against It.
                    Viscount St Aldwyn said the argu
                    ments for the extension of tho parlia
                    mentary suffrage to women, which were
                    based on the results obtained in those
                    States of the United States where it had
                    been' tried, did not apply in the United
                    Kingdom, because in those States men
                    were In the majority, while In the Brit
                    ish Isles they were in the minority.
                    Consequently, ho argued, the granting
                    of the parliamentary vote to women In
                    the British Isles would mean the hand
                    ing over the destinies of tho country
                    and of the empire to a female elec
                    torate, which, he said, was a perilous
                    step to take.
                    Among those who voted for the bill
                    were Viscount Money, of Blackburn:
                    the Archbishop of Canterbury, and the
                    Bishops of London, Hereford, Bangor,
                    and St. Asaph.
                    Those who voted against the bill in'
                    eluded the Marauls of Lansdowne. Vis
                    count Esher, the Marquis Salisbury, the
                    Earl of Halsbury, and the Duke of
                    Northumberland.
                    i Ixf i I I I 1 1 1 I 1 1 rr 1 1 I aBatxlTE 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 j 1 1 II 1 1 1' Tf
                    "MMBn lill IlI-LLIlI I J 1 1 1 1 ft
                    MMMninniiniiiiitttfi"
                    "TIZ" F
                    DR ACHING
                    Addresses by Mrs. Truman II. New
                    berry, of Detroit, national president of
                    the Needlework Guild of America, and
                    Miss Mabel T. Boardman, president of
                    the American Red Cross, featured the
                    annual meeting of the oranch presidents
                    of the Needlework Guild at the Raleigh
                    today.
                    Reports were read by Mrs. Oliver S.
                    Keely, of Philadelphia, national re
                    cording secretary. Miss Rosamond K.
                    Bender, national corresponding secre
                    tary. Mrs. D. Edwin Irvlnr. national
                    treasurer, and the v arlous brunch
                    presidents
                    More than ljo members were In at
                    tendance, and after luncheon icports
                    were continued. A reception will be
                    holri this nfternnnn a. vr. r1alr.V.
                    the members of the District of Columbia
                    -needlework Guild.
                    The officers of the guild are. Mrs.
                    llcnrv Arnold Peckham, president Miss
                    Mabel I. Uoardman, Mre. Os"ar V.. Un
                    derwood, Miss Anna B. Abbott, and Mrs.
                    Acheson F. Hassan, vice presidents:
                    Mi. George T. Dunlop. treasurer, and
                    Mrs. Richard B. Watrous, secretary.
                    Mrs. Woodrow Wilson has for years
                    been an active member of the guild, and
                    Is now honorary president of the Dis
                    trict branch.
                    f
                    Raymond Geis'er, eight, of STA ,Ala- j
                    bama avenue southeast, rldinc a' bi- I
                    cycle at Alabama avenue and Fifth j
                    street youtheat last night, was knock- j
                    ed from the wheel In a collision with j
                    an automobllp and bruised about the J
                    head and body He was taken to I
                    Casualtv Hospital. I
                    R
                    E. TIRED FEET
                    "TIZ" for chafed, puffed-up,
                    sweaty, calloused feet
                    and corns.
                    A Bargain "Every Hour on the Hour" In
                    OUR GARMENT SECTION FRIDAY
                    And Prices Are Sensationally Low
                    v...r fAAt.f.M Viit fa.t ffrol tlrr1
                    puffed up, chafed, aching, sweaty and
                    iiiey neea nz
                    fTTV molraB fnnt T.mft rlf flhl V frh
                    and sore-proof. "TIZ" takes the pain
                    pr.u nurn ngm out oi corns, tauuuaca
                    ilia UUIII'"!!'. 1 W fcMC ftiuui
                    foot-gladdener the world ha ever
                    known.
                    Get a 15-cent box of "TIZ" at any
                    drug sf' and end foot torture for a
                    whole year Never have tired, aching,
                    sweaty, smelly feet; your shoes will nt
                    fine and you'll only wish you had tried
                    "TIZ" sooner. Acept no substitute.
                    Advt
                    Are Your Affairs Upside Down
                    Send for Booklet-
                    Yonr House</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1914-05-10/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.163,-0.066,1.326,1.326,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>Wear a White Carnation
                    President Is Highly Praised
                    for Recognizing Movement
                    by Issuing National Proc
                    lamation; This la "Mothers Day."
                    Throughout the city, and In every Part
                    of the United States, the people are ob
                    serving the one day In the year dedi
                    cated to the mothers of the race.
                    Prominent "clergymen and members of
                    the laity Joined In expressions of appre
                    ciation yesterday, for the act cf the
                    President In issuing a proclamation, of
                    ficially designating the second Sunday
                    in May as Mothers' Day." This action
                    comes as a result of the Senate's adop
                    tion of the resolution offered by Senator
                    Sheppard, asking the President to offl
                    clally designate "Mothers' Day."
                    Wrnr a While Carnatton.
                    The white carnation will be wom by
                    thousands In Washington, the carnation
                    being; the symbol of "Mothers' Day."
                    Local florists, however, have served no
                    tice that the carnation supply Is short
                    this spring and it is quite likely that
                    white flowers of other varieties also will
                    be worn.
                    Mgr. William T. Russell, pastor St.
                    Patrick's Catholic Church. In. a state
                    ment prepared for the Washington Herald
                    yesterday, said:
                    "The decision of Congress and the
                    President to recognize officially, one
                    day In the year when the mothers of
                    the nation will be honored by the
                    whole people. Is a most laudable art.
                    No nation can rise higher than the
                    standard of its mothers and to the
                    mothers of America we owe what
                    ever (we have gained in the movement
                    tonard a higher and nobler type of
                    American manhood and womanhood."
                    RevTJr. Abram Simon, pastor of the
                    Washington Hebrew Congregation, also
                    commented on the observance of "Moth
                    ers' Day-"
                    'Mothers' Day." finds a most
                    hearty" welcome In the household of
                    Israel." said Dr. Simon. "With us.
                    her due and our duty have become
                    proverbial for purity, affection and
                    devotion. From the patriarchal day
                    .until this, motherhood has spoken
                    wilh a Hebrew accent. But mother
                    hood was not detached from father
                    hood obligations. It is parenthood
                    GUNS WITH IT
                    CONTINUED PIOM PACE ONE.
                    munitions f war would not only appear
                    favorably to the people of this coun
                    try 1 ut would clearly put the United
                    States government under a very consid
                    erable obligations to the big German shlpr-
                    ping Interests. This obligation wouid
                    come at a time, too when there has
                    been considerable talk in Congress of
                    'eolation against shipping pools.
                    Ilntelieit Vera Cms.
                    According to the report received from
                    Admiral Badger. the Kronprinzessln
                    Je ille reached Vera Cruz at 6 o'clock
                    yesterday morning. She had left Puerto,
                    Mexico, Frldal night, and the navy of
                    ficers figured that she had reached that
                    port Frldaj morning. This would have
                    given her plenty of time to have un
                    loaded her cargo of war materials. If
                    that nas intended.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1916-05-19/ed-1/?sp=9&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.271,-0.077,1.542,1.542,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>"Whereas, liy a Joint Resolution np
                    proved May 8th, 1914, designating tho
                    second Sunday in May as Mothers'
                    i Day and for other purposes, tho Presi
                    dent is authorized nnd requested to
                    issuo a proclamation calling upon the
                    i Government officials to display the
                    United States Flag on all Government
                    buildings, nnd tho peoplo of the
                    United States to display tho flag at
                    their homes or other suitable places
                    on tho second Sunday In May as a
                    pnblio expression of our lovo and rev
                    erence for the mothers of our country.
                    And Whereas, by the said joint Rcs
                    olution it is made tho duty of the
                    President to request the observation
                    J of the second Sunday in May as pro
                    j Tided for In the said joint Resolution;
                    Now, Therefore, I, Wooclrow Wfl
                    rj son, President of the United States
                    ;J of America, by virtue of the authority
                    vested in mo by the said Joint Rcso
                    lution, do hereby direct tho Govern-
                    i W11 above, a proclamation by the
                    3 M President of the United States,
                    i added another day to the calen
                    j dar of our national holidays and
                    yone which has a tender significance
                    j and shows a hopeful sign of the ro
                    i turn of the old-time sentiment of by
                    Igone days which for a time seemed
                    crushed out in the wild rush of com
                    nerclallsm which spread over the
                    i? land.
                    f) T"
                    merit officials to display .tho United
                    States Flag on all Government build
                    ings, and do invito tho peoplo of the
                    United States to display tho flag at
                    their homes or other suitablo places
                    on tho second Sunday in May as a
                    public expression or our lovo and rev
                    erence for tho Mothers of our coun
                    try. In witness whereof I have set my
                    hand and caused tho Seal of tho
                    United States to bo hereunto affixed.
                    Done at the City of Washington, this
                    ninth day of May, in the year of our
                    Lord One Thousand Nino Hundred and
                    Fourteen, and the Independence of the
                    United States One Hundred and Thirty-Eight,
                    WOODROW WILSON.
                    By tho President:
                    William Jennings .Bryan,
                    Secretary of State."
                    (SEAL)
                    Older Tlian Christianity
                    Tho celebration of Mothers' Day,
                    while new to us as a feast day, Is In
                    history older than Christianity Itself,
                    for Mother-worship with its rites and
                    ceremonies dates back to tho days of
                    the pagans when Cybele, tho Groat
                    Mother of Gods, was idealized in
                    Greece two centuries or more before
                    tho coming of Christ. Later tho day
                    111 HHHHHmBHSW'
                    became known as tho festival of Hll
                    arla and was hold on the Ides of
                    March. As was tho custom of tho
                    day, offerings wore made at tho tem
                    ple." With tho advent of Christianity
                    the festival was changed, and although
                    It still Included many pagan customs,
                    It becamo a celebration" In honor of
                    Mother Church and was held on Mid
                    Lent Sunday, or tho fourth Sunday In
                    Lent On this day tho faithful came
                    to bring offerings to Mother Church.
                    Finally, tho day took tho name of
                    Mothering Sunday, and was sot aside
                    as-tho time when peoplo should pay
                    visits to their paronts, especially to
                    tholr mothers, also that they should
                    carry with them some cako or trinket.
                    "Going a-mothcrlng" soon becamo tho
                    fashion and a certain kind of cako
                    known as simncl cako was carried as
                    a gift to tho mothor. Horrick, tho
                    poet, In addressing one of tho char
                    actors of his poem on Mothering,
                    says:
                    "I'll to thee a slmnel bring
                    Gainst thou go a-mothering,
                    So that when sho blessos theo,
                    Half that blessing thou'lt give me."
                    This proves that even In tho early
                    days tho mothers' blosslng was highly
                    regarded.
                    In England tho slmnel cake3 woro
                    composed of a crust made of flno flour
                    and water with sufficient saffron to
                    give it a deop yellow color and the
                    interior filled with such ingredients
                    as Is used In plum puddings. They
                    aro boiled and brushed over with egg
                    and set away to harden. When they
                    are to bo used they must bo robaked
                    and softened. This, custom was In
                    vogue during tho seventeenth century
                    when every child who resided away
                    from homo was expected to carry a
                    slmnel to his or her mothor. Fre
                    quently tho cakes wero kept until
                    Easter -and sorved ns tho desert for
                    the dinner on that day.
                    Early Celebrations
                    Mothers' Day was first observed in
                    1908 In Philadelphia by Bevoral of
                    tho Sunday schoolB, and in 1909 about
                    two thousand people took part In tho
                    services. Seattle, Washington, how
                    over, has tho honor of being tho real
                    pioneer In a genuino Mothers' Day
                    celebration. This was In 1900 when
                    hundrods of peoplo gathered in tho
                    churches of that city on tho second
                    Sunday In May. They carried bou
                    quets and wreaths of flowers and at
                    the closo of sermons on "Mothor
                    Lovo" tho entire congregations hold
                    tholr flowors aloft whllo tho pastor
                    pronounced a blessing, and at the
                    closo of tho service tho flowers were
                    gathered together and placed on the
                    graves of mothers whoso relatives
                    wero not in tho city to perform this
                    loving service.
                    In 1910 tho Governor of tho State
                    of Washington set asldo tho eighth
                    of May ot that year as Mothers' Day
                    for that Stato, and over slnco that tlmo
                    tho proclamation of Mothers' Day has
                    been issued with tho samo regularity
                    as that of Thanksgiving. A request
                    is also added that each person wear
                    a whlto flower on tho day and that
                    special services should bo held in tho
                    churches.
                    Tho Stato of Oklahoma was the next
                    to fall in lino wltha Mothers' Day
                    proclamation, whon Governor Leo
                    Cruco in 1912 paid such a glowing
                    tribute to motherhood in his procla
                    mation to tho peoplo of that Stato:
                    "Each citizen, whether old or
                    young, rich or poor, happy or -sorrowful,
                    remember her whoso
                    lovo passeth human understand
                    ing, and remembering, manifest
                    to tho world your lovo nnd gratl
                    tudo by wearing a carnation In
                    honor of tho dearest of all moth
                    ers, and wearing It, think of her
                    and love her."
                    Slnco that tlmo many Slatos have
                    followed the example of these two.
                    Western States, and at present tho day
                    has takon-'H prdrrfihent plnfo among
                    our feast days. Sermons aro preached
                    on tho subject of motherhood in the
                    majority of our churches. Tho Sun
                    day schools have a Mothors Day ser
                    vice, and In tho afternoon many go
                    out to tho cemotories to cover tho
                    gravo of "man's best friend" with gar
                    lands of flowors.
                    Mothers' Pensions
                    Tho celebration of Mothers' Day
                    has brought about a stronger feeling
                    on tho subject of pensioning mothers,
                    and ono Is surprised to learn how
                    many States havo already adopted tho
                    pensioning system for mothors who
                    aro too poor to properly caro for their
                    chlldron. Whllo the plan is too now
                    to show vory many benefits to tho
                    mother and child tho sponsors of tho
                    bill In tho City of Chicago aro of the
                    opinion that a child can bo maintained
                    at homo choaper than It can in an in
                    stitution, and also that a child with
                    a homo is less likely to turn criminal
                    than tho ono brought up in an Insti
                    tution. Tho statistics of tho Stato Re
                    formatory at Elmlra in Now York
                    Stato provo tho above .to bo true In
                    that Stato at least, sixty per cent
                    of the Inmates having been brought
                    up In Institutions instead of homes.
                    "Home with Mother" is the aim for
                    the child by the charity workors of
                    the present day. "Assist the mother
                    financially," they say, "and sho will
                    caro for her child In such a manner
                    that Stato Reformatories will not bo
                    needed. Tho preservation of tho
                    home is worth all It cost3 a Common
                    wealth." Twonty-two States are al
                    ready In lino In this work: Arizona.
                    California, Idaho, Iowa, Illinois, Mary
                    land. Massachusetts, Michigan, Min
                    nesota. Missouri, Nebraska, Nevada,
                    New Hampshire, Now Jersey, New
                    York, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Penn
                    sylvania, South Dakota, Utah. Wash
                    ington and Wisconsin.
                    Mother Influence on Statesmen
                    Tho significance of Mothers' Day
                    should find an echo in every heart,
                    for It was tho mothors of our Statos-
                    Imen who Jn the early days put our
                    'Nation on a 'firm foundation "The
                    hand that rocks the cradlo Is the hand I
                    that rules tho world." It was tho
                    mother of Georgo Washington who,
                    by hor woman's intuition that ho was
                    mado for better things, saved him
                    from becoming a midshipman on a
                    British ship. It was the turning
                    point in tho life of tho Father of his
                    Country whon rather than causo his
                    mother sorrow ho roturnod his middy
                    uniform and said "Mothor I can never
                    go and cause you so much grief. I
                    will stay at homo." With Washing
                    ton In tho British Navy thero might
                    have been no Monmouth and no York
                    town. Tho character of Androw Jackson's
                    mother stands out in Amorlcan his
                    tory like a speck of blue in tho dark
                    sky of those early days in tho moun
                    tains. Her advice to her son Bhows
                    the wisdom of Polonlus and may well
                    bo treasured by tho man who desires
                    to succood. Jackson never forgot hor
                    words of advice and a short time be
                    fore his death he repeated her part
                    ing advice to a young man in whom
                    ho was interested.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1916-06-29/ed-1/?sp=10&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.231,-0.073,1.462,1.462,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>FOUNDER OF "MOTHERS' DAY"
                    THANKS AD MEN FOR CO-OPERATION
                    Miss Anna Jarvis Gives Ad
                    vertising Men Credit for
                    Plan
                    The founder of Mother's Day and tho
                    Mother's Day International Association
                    wishes to thank with nlncero appreciation
                    every member of the Associated Advertising
                    Clubs who has ever helped for Mother's
                    Day success.
                    Mother's Day success.
                    Mother's Day was first promoted by
                    Philadelphia papers, and through the co
                    operation of the press of this and other
                    countries has been mado an International
                    celebration. No movement of the century
                    has obtained so wonderful a hold on the
                    hearts of tho peoplo under such a multi
                    tude of dinicultleH and limitations In estab
                    lishing and promoting It. Tho press, how
                    ever, has been the one stanch and good
                    friend of Mother's Day since Its early days,
                    Mother's Day Is for the honor of the
                    home, especially Its motherhood, by older
                    people as well as children, and by the na
                    tion, that must look to the home as the
                    fountain head of that which Is good and
                    true.
                    The celebration always occurs the second
                    Sunday in May In homes and churches.
                    Schools, clubs, etc., celebrate during the
                    week preceding.
                    The Mother's Day badge la tho white
                    carnation, emblem .of the beauty, truth and
                    fidelity of mother love.
                    The slogan of Mother's Day Is, "In honor
                    of the best mother who ever lived, tho
                    mother of my heart"
                    As friends of this Mother's Day move
                    ment, which so distinctly honors your own
                    mothers, will you not help us to promote
                    In our way a worldwide, simultaneous celc-
                    MISS ANNA JARVIS
                    brntlon of Mother's Day, with the white
                    carnntlon as tho emblem to be worn, on the
                    second Sunday of May, and letters or acts
                    of affection to homes, etc., ns one of tho
                    simple, easy ways of celebrating?
                    ANNA JARVIS. Founder.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95060583/1922-05-18/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.279,-0.478,1.111,2.36,0</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>MOTHER 0' MINE
                    It 1 were hanged on the highest hill.
                    Mother o' mine, O mother o mine!
                    1 know whose love would follow me still.
                    Mother o mine, O mother o' mine!
                    It I were drowned in the deepest sea.
                    Mother o mine, O mother o' mine!
                    I know whose tears would come down to
                    me.
                    Mother o' mine, O mother o' mine!
                    If I were cursed in body and soul,
                    Mother o mine, O mother o mine!
                    I know whose prayers would make me
                    whole.
                    Mother o' mine, O mother o' mine!
                    Rudyard Kipling.
                    By JOHN DICKINSON SHERMAN
                    OTHER'S Day should be
                    celebrated 365 days In
                    the year. There's no
                    need to argue about it.
                    Every man and woman
                    blessed with a good
                    mother knows it's true
                    and knows why it's true.
                    It doesn't take a very
                    old child to understand,
                    either.
                    But, since human nature is human
                    nature, every day isn't observed as
                    Mother's Day. There is all the more
                    reason, therefore, for observing the
                    second Sunday in May May 14, this
                    year with a real celebration. Some
                    one has tried to figure out a real cele
                    bration after this fashion for sons:
                    Wear a flower in mother's honor
                    a white one if mother is dead; a col
                    ored flower for a living mother.
                    Send mother a box of spring flowers.
                    Write her a letter a long one.
                    Give mother a whole day of your
                    time for that "good visit" she longs
                    for.
                    Send mother your picture, and snap
                    shots of your home, your children,
                    your work.
                    Tell mother, your plans and ambi
                    tions she made them possible.
                    Tell mother your smaller troubles
                    she wants to help you.
                    Thank mother for her care and her
                    teachings tell her how they have
                    helped you.
                    Don't forget that mother still likes
                    candy.
                    Mother was your first and truest
                    sweetheart don't forget to say "I
                    love you I"
                    For the daughters these things are
                    suggested
                    It's your chance to say "thank you"
                    to your best friend your mother.
                    Be sure to celebrate by wearing a
                    flower for mother: White for mothers
                    not living; colored flowers for mother
                    still with you.
                    Send mother some gay spring flow
                    ers, a brilliant bouquet or a thrifty
                    plant.
                    Make a dainty cap or a "dress-up"
                    gown or shirtwaist as a love gift to
                    mother.
                    If mother is far away, send her a
                    "special delivery letter" for her Sun
                    day treat.
                    Send mother the book you just en
                    Joyed reading.
                    Don't forget to send her pictures of
                    yourself, your friends and your good
                    times.
                    Tell mother your small joys and sor
                    rows and ask her advice It will be
                    good.
                    Ask mother to tell you about her
                    girlhood you'll both enjoy it.
                    Mother is a gin too. She likes pretty
                    things, love, laughter and compliments.
                    Give her some.
                    The spirit of this celebration is
                    right enough. The letter of it fails.
                    Nobody can tell you how to observe
                    Mother's Day.. You know. If she's a
                    red carnation mother make her happy.
                    If she's a white carnation mother, do
                    something that would make her happy
                    if she were a red carnation mother.
                    Nobody can draw up a celebration
                    schedule for Mother's Day. How can
                    one, when nobody can find adequate
                    words to write about Mother's Day?
                    Mother's Day is something new In
                    the way of holidays not like Christ
                    mas and Easter which are old, old
                    holidays. And It's new, compared with
                    the Fourth of July. In fact, It's just
                    about the newest holiday we have.
                    It was no longer ago than 1906 that
                    Miss Anne Jarvis of Philadelphia, hon
                    oring the memory of her own mother
                    on the anniversary of her death, con
                    ceived of a day of which everyone
                    should do reverence to his mother,
                    whether living or dead. The World's
                    Sunday School association adopted the
                    plan, and, in the next few years, an
                    nually designated one Sunday as
                    Mother's Day. The purposes of this
                    celebration, as stated by Dr. George
                    W. Bailey, then president of the asso
                    ciation, were:
                    "To recall the memories of the
                    mothers that are gone, and through
                    loving words and loving care to
                    brighten the lives of the mothers that
                    remain, and to help children, men and
                    women to a greater blessing in honor
                    ing their fathers and their mothers.
                    "To recall mother's prayers, moth
                    er's dying words, and the promises
                    made to mother by the big boy that
                    still mourns her, and to stop and think
                    a little of what she was in her life to
                    her family."
                    In 1908 Miss Jarvis founded an or
                    ganization now known as Mother's Day
                    International association.
                    The idea was taken up by the states.
                    In 1910 the governor of Washington
                    Issued a proclamation designating
                    May 8 of that year as "Mother's Day"
                    and urged It be celebrated by special
                    services and the wearing of a white
                    flower in honor of all mothers. In 1912
                    the governor of Oklahoma issued a
                    similar proclamation.
                    National recognition was given
                    Mother's Day by resolution of the
                    Sixty-third congress, approved by the
                    President of the United States on May
                    8, 1914, designating that the second
                    Sunday in May thereafter should gen
                    erally be known as "Mother's Day,"
                    and directing that it should be the
                    duty, of the President to request its ob
                    servance by Issuing a proclamation
                    calling upon the government officials
                    to display the United States flag on
                    all government buildings, and the peo
                    ple to display the flag at their homes
                    or other suitable places on this day,
                    "as a public expression of our love
                    and reverence for the mothers of our
                    country."
                    Originally the white carnation was
                    the flower worn in observance of the
                    day. Then, the public settled on white
                    carnations for mothers dead and ted
                    carnations for mothers living; then on
                    white flowers and colored flowers.
                    Now the tendency is to wear "mother's
                    favorite flower."
                    The great of the world have been
                    proud to pay tribute to mothers.
                    Unhappy is the man for whom his
                    own mother has not made all other
                    mothers venerable. Rlchter.
                    A man never sees all that his mother
                    has been to him till it's too late to
                    let her know that he sees it. W. D.
                    Howells.
                    If you would reform the world from
                    its errors and vices, begin by enlisting
                    the mothers. C. Simmons.
                    I think It must somewhere be writ
                    ten that the virtues of the mothers
                    shall be visited on their children, as
                    well as the sins of the fathers.
                    Charles Dickens.
                    The loving sacrifices of motherhood
                    must burn on the altar of undying
                    faith. If I could bequeath but one
                    priceless heritage to youth, it would
                    be the ability to know the full measure
                    of her love. Her Influence is the most
                    changeless thing in the fiber of a
                    man's character. It outweighs arts,
                    science, literature and philosophy, for
                    her faith and works are better than
                    all the wise man's knowledge. Sena
                    tor Lawrence T. Sherman.
                    Then there Is the Gold Star Mother
                    and the Mother in Time of War oh,
                    what's the use!</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-05-08/ed-1/seq-4/#date1=1756&amp;index=2&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Day+DAY+day+Mother+mother+MOTHERS&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=Mother%27s+Day&amp;y=26&amp;x=4&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>MOTHERS DAY TOMORROW! U. S. TO RE
                    SOUND WITH PRAISES AND PRAYERS FOR HER
                    Miss Anna Jarvis, the "Mother" of Mother's Day.
                    Mother will be QUEEN tomorrow.
                    She will be the sweetheart of the
                    world.
                    The carnation, symbol of maternal
                    love, will be the national flower for
                    one day at least
                    In churches, in homes, in prison
                    cells, in hospitals, in the harvest
                    fields of the west and in the slums of
                    the east, every one will pay tribute
                    to MOTHER or to MOTHER'S mem
                    ory. Miss Anna Jarvis of Piladelphia is
                    the "mother" of Mother's day. Eight
                    years ago she invited her friends to
                    Join her on May 9 in commemorating
                    the death of her mother. The annual
                    tribute to mothers, which is now a
                    world-wide custom, was the Outcome
                    of that little meeting.
                    The official program arranged by
                    Miss Jarvis for the celebration of
                    Mother's day includes the Mother's
                    day prayer, the proclamation of the
                    president recognizing Mother's day,
                    James Whitcomb Riley's poem on
                    Mother's day and the singing of na
                    tional anthems.</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1952-04-27/ed-1/seq-174/#date1=1756&amp;index=3&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Day+mother&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=Mother%27s+Day&amp;y=26&amp;x=4&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
                <rel>1</rel>
                <text>On mother’s Day (may 11th) Give Her
                    Flower-fresh, picture-pretty, purse-pleasing HjH| , ~; | a
                    cotton</text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1956-05-06/ed-1/seq-193/#date1=1756&amp;index=0&amp;rows=20&amp;words=DAY+Day+MOTHER+Mother&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=Mother%27s+Day&amp;y=26&amp;x=4&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn96027111/1909-04-30/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.056,-0.434,1.111,2.36,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1909-05-09/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.217,-0.072,1.435,1.435,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1912-05-12/ed-1/?sp=14&amp;q=Miss+Anna+Annie+Jarvis+Mothers%27+Day&amp;st=text&amp;r=-0.216,-0.072,1.431,1.431,0</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1952-04-27/ed-1/seq-172/#date1=1756&amp;index=1&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Day+Mother&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=Mother%27s+Day&amp;y=26&amp;x=4&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
            <result>
                <id>
                    https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1938-05-08/ed-1/seq-77/#date1=1756&amp;index=4&amp;rows=20&amp;words=DAY+MOTHER&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=Mother%27s+Day&amp;y=26&amp;x=4&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</id>
                <rel>0</rel>
                <text></text>
            </result>
        </results>
    </topic>
</topics>